斯坦福大学
Stanford University.
欢迎来到CS193P的第11讲
So, welcome to Lecture 11 of CS193P.
这是2013-2014学年秋季课程
This is the fall quarter of academic year 2013/2014.
今天我们将谈到两大主题
And today we're going to talk about two major topics.
一是UITableView(UI表格视图) 这是一个很重要的类
One is UI TableView, which a very important class.
我们还将谈到iPad
And also we're going to talk about an iPad now.
之前做的一切都只针对iPhone
We've been doing everything so far on the iPhone,
现在我们想同时针对iPad iPhone两个平台
but we want to start doing things actually on both platforms now; iPad and iPhone.
然后我要做一个演示
And then I'm going to do a demo, which is going
将两者结合到一起
to of course incorporate these two things.
首先看TableView
So let's dive right into TableView.
这是一个很重要的类 因为很多时候
This is a very important class, because a lot of times the data
应用程序中所要展示的数据 都是以列表的形式出现的
that you need to display in your applications comes in the form of a list.
TableView基本上也就是一个列表视图
And TableView is basically a list view.
它是一系列项目的列表
It's a list of items.
它是一维的
It's one-dimensional in that, you know, it's just --
而不是矩阵或是电子表格那些东西
it's not like a matrix or a spreadsheet or something like that.
它是一维的 不过可以分为多段
It's one, although it can be divided into sections
这就让它能有更多维度
which gives it a little more dimension.
当我们要展示多维数据时 例如电子表格的情况
When we want to display multiple dimension things like a spreadsheet would be,
我们可以将多个TableView放入到导航控制器中
then we just put multiple TableViews into navigation controllers.
用户触碰各行 我们滑动到下一行
And so users touch rows and we slide in the next row basically
或者说下一列 考虑电子表格这类情况就是如此
or next column, if you want to think of it in spreadsheet-type terms.
这就是我们的做法
So that's how we do it.
TableView本身并不能处理多维数据
The TableView itself doesn't manage multidimensional data.
TableView还有很多配置选项和自定义
And there's a lot of different configuration and customizations for TableViews.
我将有一些幻灯片来展示这些TableView是怎样的
And so I have some slides here to show you some pictures of what TableViews look like.
这里有一些不同类型的TableView
So here's a couple of different types of TableViews --
这是两种主要类型 左边是普通样式
the two main types -- which is the plain style, that's the one on the left.
右边则是分组样式
And then the group style which is the one on the right.
普通样式这个同时也是动态TableView
The plain style one that I've shown there is also a dynamic TableView.
也就是说 所有内容都是填充自某处的数据库
Meaning that all of its contents are being filled up from some database somewhere.
例如这里 我有一些联系人
So you can see here I've got some contacts there.
你们有些人估计能够猜出他们是做什么的
Some of you might be able to guess what all those people are.
无论如何 这里只是来自某数据库的一份列表
But anyways, it's just a list from some database --
团队数据库这之类
a team database or something.
而右边这个
And then on the right.
是一个分组表格
We have a grouped table.
可以看到 数据都分好了组
You can see the kind of -- the things are grouped, right?
有距离分组
The little distances section.
地图标签分组 这里有更多的分组
The map label section they're kind of grouped together more instead
不像左边 只有题名
of just having section titles on the left.
而且 右边这个是静态的
And also, that one on the right is static.
换言之 其中的项目
In other words, the things that are
并不来自于某个数据库
in that aren't coming out of a database.
它们只是设定在这里
They're just kind of fixed in there.
总是"以英里计"和"以公里计"
It always says in miles. It always says in kilometers.
总是"英文"
It always says all this in English.
这是固定不变的
It's just fixed.
所以说表格是静态的
So it's a static table.
这两种类型涵盖了我们可以考虑的所有样式
So these two kind of encompass all the different styles that we can do.
我们再来看下TableView的各个部分
So let's talk about some of the particular parts of a TableView.
我会告诉你们它们都叫什么 便于讨论
I'm just going to give them some names so we can talk about them.
在TableView顶部有一个视图
So at the top of the TableView, there's a view.
它处于所有行之上
That comes before all the rows,
这是header 表头
which is the header -- the table header.
最下面有一行代码
There's a little bit of code at the bottom.
便于以后参考
That's more for your reference later.
这是TableView中用于设定属性的
That's basically the properties you use to set that thing in the TableView.
当然 这里还有一个footer
And of course there's the footer as well.
之前是页头 这里是页尾
So the table header and a table footer.
中间是所有这些行
In between is where all the rows are.
这些行会被分为多段(section)
And the rows are divided into sections.
每一段包括多行 也可以是一行
And each section includes some rows -- some number of rows could be one row.
也可以是一百行 一千行等等
Or it could be 100 rows. Or a 1,000 rows, whatever.
它们也有header和footer
And also a header and a footer.
每一段有段头 这两段有header 0和header 1
So each section has headers, so you can see header 0, header 1 for these two sections.
这个TableView中有两段 每一个也都有段尾
We have two sections in this TableView, and each one also has footers.
段尾其实用得不多
We don't really use the footers that much.
不过TableView中有分段时 段头会用得很多
We use the headers quite a bit when we have sections in our TableView.
然后很重要的是 这里还有表格单元格(cell)
And then very importantly, there's the table cells.
这是来自数据库的实际数据
And this is where the actual data that's coming
或是我们在TableView中显示的别的东西
out of our database, or whatever, that we're displaying in our TableView
我们将它们放到这些表格单元格中
are coming out of and putting into these table cells,
它们实际上是UIView
which are actually UI views.
UIView的自定义子类
A custom subclass of UI View.
这是这里各部分的名称
So that's what we call all of these various parts.
这是普通样式中的情况
This is what it looks like in the plain style.
这是分组样式中的情况
And this is the same things in the group style.
分组样式中背景更灰一些
So the group style you see kind of this little more grey background and kind
将各段组合到一起也更多一些
of groups the sections together a little more.
我来讲一下这些段
Let me talk a little bit about the sections,
因为这有时会让人困惑
because sometimes that confuses people.
段只是将行组织起来的一种方式
A section is just a way to group the rows.
左边的信息是没有分段的
So here I've got some information with no sections.
这是一系列城市
It's just a bunch of cities.
赫尔辛基 巴黎 柏林
Right? Helsinki and Paris and Berlin.
而右边还是一份城市列表
And on the right I've also got a list of cities,
不过我按国家将它们分到了不同的段中
but they're grouped into sections by the country.
这里有日本
You can see Japan.
其中有东京 京都 然后是墨西哥
It's got Tokyo and Kyoto and the Mexico.
这里有旧金山 还有荷兰
It's got San Francisco, something or other there, and Netherlands.
它有阿姆斯特丹
It has Amsterdam.
这里按国家分了组 不过仍然是一份城市列表
So they're grouped by country, but it's still just a list of cities.
这就是段
So that's the sections.
你们在作业中就需要
They're not -- now in your homework you're actually going
做和这里一样的事
to have to do, in fact this exact thing.
也就是按国家对地名进行分组
Where you're going to be grouping places by the country they're in.
你们在作业中需要用到section
And so you will be using sections in your homework.
在今天的演示中 我将不会用到section
In the demo today I'm not going to do sections.
你们需要自己在作业中搞清楚
I have to leave you something to figure out on your homework.
单元格类型
The type of cell.
每个单元格 每一行 可以有特定类型
So each cell -- each row -- can have a certain types.
有一个副标题类型 有标题和副标题
There's the subtitle type that has like a title and a subtitle there.
可以看到城市和国家
You see the city and then the country --
地区和国家作为副标题给出
or the region and the country there is the subtitle.
基本类型则没有副标题
And then basic has no subtitle.
然后还有右侧细节和左侧细节两种
There's the right detail and the left detail.
将副标题信息推到边上
That puts that subtitle information kind of off
然后用点颜色字体来修饰
to the side with a little bit of color or whatever.
这些是单元格的四种不同类型
So these are the four different types of cells.
你还可以自定义单元格
And you can also have custom cells.
完全自己进行布局
Where you lay out what's in there completely on your own.
如何使用TableView呢
So how do you use a TableView?
99%的时候 我们都会和TableView控制器一起用
Well 99% of the time we use it with a TableView Controller.
TableView控制器可以直接拖出来
So TableView Controller you can just drag it right out.
这里我们有Xcode
So here we have X-code.
这里有TableView控制器应用程序示例
I've got this TableView Controller example application
我只需要从对象面板中拖出一个TableView控制器
here, and I'm just dragging a TableView Controller out of the object pallet
放到故事板中 这就得到了一整个场景
and into my storyboard and it puts a whole scene there.
这个场景的控制器是一个UITableView控制器
Now that scene's controller is a UITableView Controller.
这是iOS中的一个类 UITableViewController
That's a class in IOS. UI TableView Controller.
这个UITableViewController场景的视图是
The view of that UI TableView Controller scene is a
一个UITableView
UI TableView.
使用UITableViewController时 几乎总有
When we use UI TableView Controller almost always the
整个视图是一个UITableView
entire view is a UI TableView.
视图的复杂性来自于单元格 我们将什么放到单元格中
The complexity in that view comes in the cells -- what we put in the cells.
这是信息和数据所在的地方
That's where the information and the data is.
我们一般不会放一个TableView
We don't usually put a TableView
然后再在它周围放些别的什么
and then some other things around it.
虽然你可以这样做
Although you can do that,
但一般而言 你不会这样使用UITableViewController
you just usually wouldn't use UI TableView Controller in that case.
你只需要
You're going to do kind
手动去做UITableViewController为你准备的所有事情
of all the things UI TableView Controller does for you, manually --
等下我会具体提到都有些什么
which I'll mention what some of those things are.
好 我们把这个拖出来
Alright? So we just drag this thing out.
这里我们显然希望它是UITableViewController的子类
We are obviously going to want to subclass UI TableView Controller
这样我们就能实现我们自己的控制器行为
so that we can implement our own controller behavior for one thing.
viewDidLoad等等
View did load and all those things.
此外 我们还要实现
But also we're going to want to implement
TableView的委托和数据源
the TableView's delegate and data source.
也就是一些属性 它们具有协议 后面我会讲到
Which are a couple of properties that have a protocol, which we're going to talk about.
这就是数据载入表格的方式
And that's how the data gets loaded in the table.
所有这些东西都将在UITableViewController的子类中完成
So we're going to do all that stuff in a subclass of UI TableView Controller.
可以看到 我正在创建一个新文件
So you can see that I did new file, and now I'm creating it,
它是UITableViewController的子类
and you can see that it's a subclass of UI TableView Controller and I'm calling it
名字用"MyTableViewController"(我的表格视图控制器)
my -- actually probably "My TableView Controller" is what I should
下面这里应该是它 没错
call it -- might have called it that on the next one yeah I did.
然后和很多场景一样
And then of course, just like any other scene, you're going
你需要点击控制器 并到标识符检查器中设置类
to click on the controller and go over to the identity inspector and set the class.
这同其它控制器的做法没有两样
That's exactly the same as you've done for all your controllers, right?
你需要设置类 这里我将它设置到MyTableViewController
You have to set the class, so here I'm setting it to My TableView Controller.
这两张幻灯片有点不同步
A little out of sync between those two slides.
不管它 这里取名叫MyTableViewController
Anyway, My TableView Controller we'll call it.
如果我右键点击这个控制器
And if I right-click on that controller.
看看这里有什么连接
And see what its connections are,
在黑框底部的是引用输出口
you'll see that at the bottom of that black window there's referencing outlets.
这里是两个属性 数据源和委托
Those are two properties -- datasource and delegate --
这些是ID 尖括号 UITableViewDataSource
those are ID angle bracket. UI TableView Datasource,
或ID 尖括号 UITableViewDelegate
or ID angle bracket, UI TableView Delegate.
TableViewController拖出来后
And the TableView controller, when we drag it out,
就会自动成为这两个东西
automatically sets itself to be those two things.
这两个协议中的所有方法都会
So all the methods in those two protocols are going to be implemented
被我们这里的TableViewController实现
by our TableView Controller subclass right there.
当然 我们会从UITableViewController中继承一些
And of course we're actually going to inherit some of them from UI TableView Controller
这些都是处理TableView时 iOS为我们提供的现成东西
which is this nice package that IOS provides to kind of get you going with TableView's.
我们等下会谈到数据源和委托
And we're going to talk about the datasource and the delegate and what they --
这里有哪些方法
what methods are in there and what we have
以及如何让这些发挥作用
to do to make this all work in just a moment.
不过首先 看看如何配置TableView
But first, let's look a little bit of how we can configure the TableView
让它看起来有所不同
and make it look different ways.
TableView默认是普通样式
This TableView comes out and it's in plain style by default,
我打算换成分组样式 看看会是怎样
but I'm going to switch it to grouped so we can see what that looks like.
似乎很类似
It looks kind of similar.
只是周边有一个灰色区域
Again, more of a grey around it -- more grey area because the cell --
这样各行就分组得更好一些
the rows are kind of grouped together more.
这些单元格现在是动态的
These are dynamic cells right now.
也就是说 数据是从外部加载的
In other words, they would be loaded by some external data,
使用我们的数据源协议
using our datasource protocol.
不过我要把这些转换成静态单元格
But I'm going to switch this to static cells.
转换成静态单元格后
And when you switch to static cells,
它会给我三行 而不是一行 这很棒
first of all it gave me three instead of one, which was nice.
现在 这些单元格成了静态的
Now these cells are static.
也就是说 无论我在故事板中怎么编辑它们
Meaning however I edit them in the storyboard,
这就会成为它们在程序中的样子
that's what they're going to look like in the program.
它们不是从外部数据源加载的
They're not getting loaded up from any external datasource,
只是我在这里编辑的
I'm just editing them right here.
几乎就像是三个矩形的视图
It's almost like it's just three rectangular views.
你可以把按钮或是标签拖到这里
And you can drag buttons in here. You can drag labels.
也可以接通输出口
You can wire up outlets.
你可以在静态TableView中做任何你想做的事
You can do anything you want in this static TableView.
静态TableView是为设置这些所设计的
Really the static TableView is for things like settings and things like that.
它们的UI是固定的
Things that, you know, are -- the UI of them is fixed.
并不适用于联系人这些
It's not for, you know, contacts and things
否则就需要数据库加载 这里只是静态
where you're loading it out of a database. So you can have static.
不过现在 我打算转换回动态
But I'm going to switch back to dynamic here.
转换回动态单元格
Back to the dynamic cells.
转换回动态单元格后
So -- and notice that when I switch
注意它在顶部说 原型单元格
to dynamic cells it says along the top, prototype cells.
因为这些单元格将成为原型
Because these cells are actually going to be prototypes --
无论我们在故事板中怎么做
whatever we do here in the storyboard --
这些都会被复制到
that are going to be replicated over and over
数据库中加载的一切数据上
for everything that comes out of our database.
动态模式中 我们从数据库中获得数据
So in dynamic mode we're getting all the data out of the database
并复制这些原型
and we're replicating these prototypes.
而且 这还是在分组模式中
Also, this is still in grouped mode.
我打算切换回普通模式
So I'm going to switch back to plain mode.
上面还是说原型单元格
It still says prototype cells to the top,
不过这里我回到了普通模式
but now I'm getting more of the plain mode
没有灰色区域和分组这些
where there's not the grey around the group so much.
这里还三行
Also you can see I have three of them there.
三个原型单元格很不寻常
It's pretty unusual to have three different prototype cells
从数据库中加载数据时
when you're loading the stuff out of the database.
只有加载的是完全不同的东西时
It would only be if you're loading kind of different things
你才需要使用不同显示方式和不同的原型
out of the database and you display them differently you might have different prototypes.
不过大多数时候 原型只有一种
But most of the time we only have one.
因此 这里我将切换回一个原型单元格
So I'm going to change back to one prototype cell.
这里只有一个原型单元格
So I have this one prototype cell.
它会被复制到数据库中加载的每一行数据
It's going to be copied for every single thing that I load out of my database; every row.
明白什么是原型了吗
Does everybody understand what I'm saying by it's a prototype?
可以说是一个被复制的模板
It's like a template that's going to be copied.
在故事板中所进行的任何设置
So whatever we do here in the storyboard to set this thing up,
都会沿用下去
it's going to look the same.
只有数据会发生变化
Except the data will be different because it's going
数据是从数据库中加载的 但布局什么的会不变
to be loaded from a database, but the layout of it is going to look the same.
我们能做些什么呢
So what kind of things can we do?
下面让这些单元格具有副标题
Well, let's change this cell to have that subtitle look
得到副标题类型的单元格
like a subtitle thing that we -- cell type okay?
这时有标题和副标题
And so now we get a title and a subtitle.
从数据库中获取每一行的数据时
So when we pull data out of our database, we're going to want
我们既希望获取标题
to pull some data that's the title
也希望获取副标题信息
and pull some data that's the subtitle for each row.
我们还可以在行右侧附加一点信息
We can also add a little accessory on the right-hand side of the row.
这里我打算加一点特殊的 所谓细节披露
So I'm going to put a special one in here, a detailed disclosure.
看到这里有个信息圈吧
You see it looks like that little information circle, right?
圆圈中有一个i
An "I" inside of a circle.
这其实是一个很特殊的东西
And that's actually a special thing --
以后我还会讲到 不过这里还有其它东西
which I'm going to talk a little bit about later -- but there's other ones there.
比如可以是勾勾
You can put like check marks
或是披露指示器这些
and just disclosure indicators and things like that.
单元格中你可以做哪些事 我不打算全部讲到
And I'm not going to go through all the things you can do to set up the cell you want.
你还可以将图片拖进来 等等
You can drag images in there and all that stuff, but
这里我只想说
suffice it to say,
你可以在这里用检查器 按照你想要的方式设置单元格
you can use the inspector there and set your cell up the way you want.
这个单元格将在动态TableView中复制给每一行
So this cell is going to be duplicated for every row now in my dynamic table view.
对于TableView单元格来说 属性检查器中
The most important attribute though to set in the attributes inspector
最重要的是设置这个标识符
for a TableView cell is this identifier.
这里我在
You see where I've typed
标识符下键入Flickr Photo Cell(Flickr照片单元格)
in Flickr Photo Cell right there under identifier?
这段字符串我们将用于代码中
This is the string that we're going to use in our code
让代码知道复制哪个单元格
so that our code knows the cell to replicate.
就像我们在segue中做的一样
So you know, just like when we did a segue
我们会键入segue的名称 例如显示照片或是别的什么
and we would type in the name of a segue like display photo or something like that?
这些然后会被用于代码 根据名称
And that -- and then we used it in our code by name?
Xcode使用名称在代码和故事板之间进行同步
Xcode uses names to sync up between your code and what's in the storyboard.
因为你需要复制粘贴整个整个的场景
Because you want to be able to copy and paste entire scenes
例如从一个故事板到另一个故事板 你希望它们
from one storyboard to another, for example, and you want them
到新地方时能和原来的地方关联起来
to hook back up when they get to the new place.
这些都是通过名称来的
And they do that because by names.
只要名称匹配
As long as the names match.
类名
Names of classes.
标识符名 这时就能关联起来
Names of identifiers, then it will be hooked back up.
演示中 我就会复制粘贴整个的场景
And we're going to see that in the demo. I'm going to copy and paste an entire scene
从另一个应用程序复制到我的演示程序
from a completely different application that we wrote into my demo application
这些都会关联起来 这非常酷
and it's all going to stay hooked up. Which is really kind of cool.
有些人可能会觉得这些字符串太笨拙了
So some people think this is kind of unwieldy to have these strings.
你需要在代码中匹配起来
And you have to match them up in your code,
不小心输错了一个字符 你就无法匹配
and if you mistype a character, now they don't match up anymore.
反正 这里不过是用命名来关联这些东西
But it's really just using naming to hook these things up.
这很重要 这个标识符
So that's very important, that identifier, and we're going
等下代码中我们就会看到它
to see that in the code in just a moment.
好 我们再看看这两种重要的协议
Okay. So let's talk about these two really important protocols.
数据源协议和委托协议
The datasource protocol. And the delegate protocol.
数据源协议
The datasource protocol --
也就是 ID 尖括号 TableViewDataSource
which is ID angle bracket TableView datasource --
这是TableView的内容
that is the contents of the TableView.
这是从数据库出来 进入表格的数据
That's the data that's coming out of our database that's going into the table.
换言之 这是关于显示的是什么
In other words it's the what that is being displayed.
也就是显示我们的模型
It's basically displaying our model.
记得我们的模型是什么吗
And remember our model is what?
数据源将模型引入到表格中
The datasource brings the model into the table.
数据源是一种协议 由控制器实现
The controller uses -- the datasource is a protocol implemented by the controller
将模型的数据给到视图 TableView
to bring the model's data into the view -- the TableView.
另一方面 委托是关于表格如何显示的
The delegate on the other hand, is for how the table is displayed.
如何排列事物
How we arrange things.
用什么视图显示这些header和footer 诸如此类
What views we use to show those headers and footers; those kinds of things.
如果用户触碰一行会怎样
What if someone touches a row?
我们希望作出响应
And we want to react to that.
这都是委托
That's all the delegate.
无关显示的数据
It's not about the data that's being displayed,
而是如何显示这张表格
it's more like how are we displaying this table
如何对触碰作出响应 诸如此类
and how is it reacting to touches and things like that.
这两种我都会讲到 数据源和委托
So we're going to talk about both of these delegates -- the datasource and the delegate.
UITableViewController 我讲清楚一些
The UI TableView Controller, just to be clear --
前几张幻灯片中我讲过
I showed this a couple slides ago --
它会自动关联到数据源和委托
it automatically wires itself up as the datasource and delegate.
如果你要使用一个通用视图控制器
If you were going to bring out a generic view controller and drag
并将TableView拖到它里面
out a TableView into it -- which you can do.
这时你就需要自己动手将数据源和委托
You would have to control drag the datasource and the delegate
Control拖动拖到你的试图控制器并关联起来
to your view controller yourself. You'd have to hook them up.
或者在代码中关联 反正是要关联起来
Or in code you could hook them up too. But you have to connect them up.
而UITableViewController会自动关联起来
But UI TableView controller automatically hooks it up.
数据源和委托几乎总是你的控制器
The datasource and delegate are almost always going to be your controller.
这很显然 应为控制器的工作就是
That just makes sense because the controller's job is
为视图解释模型的信息
to interpret the information of the model for the view.
很显然 控制器希望是委托
So obviously the controller wants to be the delegate.
回到我们第一天讲的MVC
And again, back to the MVC thing that we did the very first day,
这是视图和控制器之间一种盲的 结构化的通信
this is that blind, structured communication between the view and the controller.
UITableViewController还有一个属性
The UI TableView Controller also has a property
叫tableView 让你能够得到控制器中的TableView
called TableView which lets you get the TableView that's in your controller.
这很好 这样你就能对它进行配置
So that's nice to be able to do that so you can configure it
同它通信等等
and talk to it and things like that.
这很棒
So that's a nice one.
它其实是self.view
It actually happens to be self.view
在TableViewController中 这有些奇特
in a TableView controller which is a little weird.
我认为这是苹果方面的奇怪设计 总之 它就是这样了
That was a strange design choice I think on Apple's part, but it is what it is.
好 数据源协议中有哪些重要的方法呢
Okay. So what are the important methods in this datasource protocol?
重要的有三个
Well, there's really three important ones.
一是 表格中有多少个section
One is, how many sections are in this table?
每一个section中有多少行
How many rows are in each section?
然后给我一个视图 一个UITableViewCell
And then give me a view -- a UI TableView cell --
给我一个视图 让我能够画出这一行
give me a view that I can use to draw this row.
很显然 就这三个方法
Obvious, right? These are the three things.
知道有多少数据 然后
Know how much data there is, and then it just asks --
持续通过这些来请求数据
constantly asks you for the data by asking for these --
这个视图
this view.
这个UITableViewCell 不断往复
This UI TableView cell over and over.
我们先讲最后一个 因为这个最重要
So let's cover the last one first, because that's the most important.
section数和行数很简单 只是请求一个数字
It's really easy; the sections and rows, it's just asking you for a number.
但为每一行获得单元格就难一些了
But the -- getting the cell for each row is a little more complicated,
我们先来看这个
so let's talk about that one first.
这是数据源协议中的第三个方法
So this is the third method in the datasource protocol.
方法名叫 TableView cellForRowAtIndexPath
And it's called, "TableView Cell for Row and Index Path".
你应该能预计到它会叫这个
It's kind of exactly what you'd expect it to be called,
可以理解 indexPath(索引路径)是一个对象
in the sense, once you understand that index path is just an object
描述section和section中的行
that describes the section and row within that section.
indexPath是一个对象
So index path is an object.
它有两个属性 row和section
It has two properties; row and section.
这个参数相当于是将行和section封装到了
So that argument is basically just encapsulating the
一个对象之中
row and section into one object.
我们被要求提供一个单元格
So that -- so we're being asked here to provide a cell --
一个UITableViewCell
a UI TableView cell,
这是一个将那一行画到那个section中的UIView
which is a UI view to draw that row in that section.
我们只对动态表格这样做
And we only do this for dynamic tables.
因为对于静态表格
Because for a static table we set all this
所有这些都在故事板中设置
up in the storyboard, so we don't need --
TableView不需要问我们要这个视图
you know, there's no need for the TableView to be asking us
因为故事板中已经设定好了
for this view, because it's already set up in the storyboard.
只有动态表格中才有这些
This is only for dynamic ones that we have this.
这里我们需要做哪两件事呢
And what are the two things that we need to do in here?
一是 我们需要创建一个单元格
One is, we need to create a cell.
然后 我们需要对单元格进行配置
And then we need to configure that cell.
我们将单独谈到这两点
So we're going to talk about those two things separately.
首先 如何创建一个我们要返回的单元格呢
First of all, how do we create a cell that we're going to return?
因为我们需要返回一个单元格 UITableViewCell
Because we have to return a cell here -- UI TableView cell.
这里需要用到一个很特别的函数
And we do that using this kind of funky method called,
dequeueReusableCellWithIdentifier: forIndexPath:
"dequeue Reusable Cell with Identifier for Index Path".
它的作用是回到故事板
Okay now, what this does is it essentially goes and looks in the storyboard.
找到标识符 Flickr Photo Cell
Finds that identifier -- Flickr Photo Cell --
我说过 这在故事板中很重要 记得吧
remember I told you that was an important thing to type in, in the storyboard.
它会复制一份原型
And it copies that prototype -- makes a copy of that prototype.
并返回它
And returns it.
不过 它的作用要比这更复杂一些
However, it's a little more sophisticated than that,
dequeueReusableCell(出列可再用单元格)是说 它只创建
and the reason it's called dequeue Reusable Cell, is that it only creates those things
行在屏幕上的那些
for the rows that are on-screen.
TableView中可能有一千行
I might have a thousand rows in my TableView
但我不希望创建一千个视图
and I don't want to make a thousand views.
否则会非常低效
That would be incredibly inefficient.
我将只创建9个视图
So I only make nine views.
因为屏幕上只能容纳9行
Because only nine rows can fit at --
这里假设是9行 也可能是15 7 4或别的多少
let's say 9, it could be 15, 7, 4, whatever.
屏幕上能放多少
However many will fit on-screen,
这里就创建这么多
I'm just going to make that many.
沿TableView往下滚动时
And as I scroll through my TableView,
一些行会从屏幕上方离开
as rows go off the top of the screen, I'm going to grab
我会把其视图放到再利用池中
that view and put it into a little reuse pool.
有新的从底下过来时
And then when a new one comes on the bottom,
我就会再用它
I'm going to reuse it.
这里我只使用屏幕上的这些
So I'm basically going to just, you know, only using the ones on screen.
离开屏幕时
And when they go off screen,
我会将其用于新出现在屏幕上的
I reuse it for a new one that's coming on-screen.
能理解吗
Does that make sense?
我是在不断再利用这些东西
So I'm just constantly re-using these things.
所以叫作dequeueReusableCell
So that's why it's called dequeueReusableCell.
但是 如果没有可以再利用的 它就会复制原型
But if I don't have one, if there's not one to reuse, it copies that prototype that's
从故事板中 使用这个名称
in the storyboard, using this name.
这方面有问题吗 请讲
Questions about that? Yeah?
学生：请明确一下
> Just a quick clarification.
你说访问TableView实际上是self.view
You said that to access the TableView it was actually self.view?
但我们进入TableView时 情况会不会有所不同
But when we get into TableView are we looking at something different?
教授：我说self.tableView等价于self.view
> Okay. When I said that self.tableview is the same as self.view,
这仅限于UITableViewController之中
that's only in UI TableView Controller.
这是一个实现细节
That's an implementation detail
我讲这个是为了避免你们被它绊倒
that I say because it might trip you up.
不过我们将总是使用self.tableView
But we always would use self.tableview.
我们永远不会用self.view 我们不能
We would never use self.view; we couldn't.
实际上 调用dequeueReusableCellWithIdentifier
In fact, we tried to call deque Reasonable Cell with identifier
在self.view下编译器会报错
with self.view, the compiler would complain.
因为self.view是UIView
Because self.view is a UI view.
它不实现这个方法
It doesn't implement that method.
self.tableView则是UITableView
Self.tableview is a UI TableView.
它才实现
It does.
问得很好
Good question though.
好 就这样 我得到了一个单元格
Alright. So anyway, this is how I get a cell.
我得到了一个UITableViewCell  这是UIView的子类
So I'm getting UI TableView Cell -- remember that's a subclass of UI View.
下面我需要加载其中内容
And now I need to load it up basically.
需要加载内容时 我可以查阅
And the way I load it up is I just go look
UITableViewCell的说明文档 看我能用它做什么
at the documentation for UI TableView Cell and I see what I can do in there.
其中一点是 它有一个属性叫
And one thing, for example, is it has a property called,
textLabel 这是一个UILabel
"Text Label", which is a UI label.
在带副标题的单元格中绘制"Title"这个词的正是它
That happens to be the thing that draws the word "Title" in those subtitled cells.
记得那些单元格吗 其中写有Title和Subtitle
Remember we saw the cells there that said title and subtitles?
这是绘制"Title"的 这里我有cell.textLabel
That's the thing that draws the title, so I just get that cell.textlabel.
我将它的文本设置为来自数据库的某些文本
I set its text to be some text that's coming out of my database
在这个行和section处
at that row and section.
我可以调用任何我要的东西
And I can call it anything I want here.
还有cell.detailTextLabel.text
There's also cell.detailtextlabel.text.
这将设置副标题
That allows me to set that little subtitle.
我还可以设置图像 我可以做各种事情
I can set the image. There's all kinds of things I could do.
我还可以创建UITableViewCell的子类
I could even subclass UI TableView Cell,
将我自己的视图放到那里 创建到它们的输出口
and put my own views in there and create outlets to them
疯狂使用TableViewCell每一行中的内容
and go crazy with what's in each row of the TableView cell.
这是可以无限扩展的
So it's infinitely expandable.
一般 我们只是这样设置UITableViewCell
Well basically we just set this UI TableView Cell to look like we want,
基于来自数据库的信息 匹配行和section
based on what information's coming out of the database that matches that row and section.
就这些了 然后我们返回单元格
And that's it. And then we return the cell.
TableView会用它来绘制这一行
And the TableView uses it to draw that row.
好 这方面有问题吗
Okay. Any questions about that?
好 这是这个
Okay so that's it.
另外两点是有多少section 有多少行
So now the only other two ones are how many sections and how many rows.
也就是这两个方法
And that's just these two methods.
TableView中section的数目
Number of sections in TableView.
如果你不实现numberOfSectionsInTableView
If you don't implement number of sections in TableView,
它会是默认值1
it actually has a default, which is one.
不实现numberOfSectionsInTableView时 它就是一大段
So if you don't implement number of sections in TableView, it's all one big section.
这是默认设置
That's kind of the default.
另一点 是每个section中有多少行
The other one, how many rows are in each section?
每个section它都会重复问你
It's going to ask you that repeatedly for every section.
这里没有默认值 你必须明确
There's no default there, so this one's required. You must say
每个section中有多少行
how many rows are in each section.
如果只有一个section 你回答这个就行了
If you only had one section, you could obviously just answer that.
这就是演示中我们要做的
That's what we're going to do in our demo.
不过section也可以不止一个
But you could have multiple sections like you will
作业中就是这样 有不同国家
with your homework when you have the countries.
有些国家有两个城市 有些则有十二个
Some countries will have two cities in them; some countries will have 12.
你需要对每个section正确回答这个问题
And you'll have to answer this question correctly for every section.
静态表格呢
What about a static table?
静态表格中这些不需要做
You don't have to do any of this for a static table.
不需要管cellForRowAtIndexPath
You don't have to do self for row at index path.
不需要管numberOfSectionsInTableView
You don't have to do number of sections of table.
不需要管numberOfRowsInSection
You don't have to do number of rows and sections.
UITableViewController把这一切都跟你打理好了
It's all just taken care for you by UI TableView Controller.
静态 只需要在故事板中编辑即可
So static, just edit in storyboard how you want it;
这些东西都不需要担心
and don't worry about any of this stuff for that.
此外还有一些方法
There's a bunch of other methods
在数据源协议中 不过我们不打算讲
in this datasource protocol that we're not going to talk about.
主要是获取header和footer的标题
They're mostly about getting the titles of the headers and the footers.
你需要用到返回header字符串名的那个
You will need the one that returns the name of the string for a header,
因为你会有一个header
because you're going to have a header --
一个section header
a section header --
作业中 这将是国家名
and it's going to be the name of the country in your homework.
另外 这些表格还可以编辑
There's also -- these tables can be edited.
行可以删除
Rows can be removed.
可以四处移动
They can be moved around.
可以调整顺序
Change the order.
等等
All that stuff.
这需要同模型保持同步
It has to be kept in sync with the model,
数据源协议中有一些方法
and so there are methods in the datasource protocol
让你知道行移动和删除中事情发生在什么时候
that lets you know when things are happening in the rows moving and deleting,
这样就能同模型保持更新
so you can keep it up to date with your model.
有问题
Question?
学生：行的数目
> Is the number of rows
对于每个section都是一样的吗
in the section something that's the same for every section?
还是说你需要声明…
Or do you declare --
教授：好 问题是 每个section中的行数是否都一样
> Okay, so the question is, is number of rows in section the same for every section?
答案是 当然不是
And the answer is absolutely not.
因为有些国家只有两个城市 这时只返回2
Because some countries only have two cities, so you'd return two
这是询问这个section时的情况
when it asks you about that section.
有些国家则有十个城市
Some countries would have ten.
这时就会返回10
So you'd return ten.
这个问题会一直重复问你
So you're going to be asked that question repeatedly,
每个section都要问一次 每个中的行数显然可以不同
once for every section and the answer could be definitely different for each one.
好 以上是数据源
Okay. So that's it for the datasource.
另一个是UITableViewDelegate
The other one is called the UI TableView Delegate.
重复一次 这个更多的是关于
And this one, again, is more how we're going
如何显示表格 而不是关于数据内容
to display this table; not what the data is we're displaying.
数据源和委托通常可以是相同的对象
And it's common though for the datasource and the delegate to be the same object,
也就是你的控制器
namely your controller.
因为TableView只是一个视图
Because the TableView is part of the view -- it's just a view.
TableView是UIView 它是视图的一部分
TableView is a UI view, it's part of your view.
因此 数据源和委托会使用你的控制器
So datasource delegate uses your controller.
委托还能让你观察到表格中发生着什么
The delegate lets you observe what's going on in the table too.
将要做这个 确实做了那个
Always will do this; did do that.
一个很有趣的是 用户确实选择了一行
And one especially interesting one is user did select a row.
委托协议可以告诉你 用户什么时候轻击了某一行
So the delegate protocol can tell you when the user tapped on a row.
大多数时候 用户轻击时 我们会segue跳转
Now we're going to -- mostly when the user taps in a row we're going to segue --
等下我会讲到
which I'm going to talk about in a moment --
不过也有可能实现这个方法
but it's also possible to implement this method
在UITableViewDelegate中
in the UI TableView delegate
叫作tableView: didSelectRowAtIndexPath
protocol called TableView:did selectrowatindexpath.
或许正是你所想的 它告诉你索引路径
Exactly what you think. It tells you the index path.
也就是发生触碰的section和行 你可以做点什么
In other words the section and row where something was touched, and you can do something.
这里你会做什么呢
Now what would you ever do in here?
如果是segue跳转 这里你将什么也不做
Well if you're segueing, you wouldn't do anything in here.
但如果是在iPad上 触击一个表格时
But if you're on the iPad, when you touch on a table,
或许你更新的东西已经在屏幕上了
maybe the thing you're updating is already on screen.
你不需要segue跳转 它已经在那里了
You're not going to segue to it, it's already on there.
因为iPad很大 它有足够空间这么做
Because the iPad's so big, it's got room to do that.
今天的演示中我们会看到
And we'll see that in the demo today.
我们有一张图 点击表格行 它会展示一张图
We're going to have an image where we click on a table row and it shows an image.
而这张图已经在屏幕上了
And that image viewing thing is already going to be on screen.
我们不需要segue跳转 它已经在那
So we don't want to segue to it, it's already there.
我们只需要更新
So we just need to update it and now we're going to do
我们会在这个方法中做到 你们会看到是怎么做的
that in this method so you can see how that works.
记得之前我展示的那个圆圈i吗
Remember that little circled I that I showed you earlier?
也就是特殊细节披露
That special detail disclosure thing?
点击它时 通常点击行时发生的事件不会发生
When you tap on it, it won't do what the row normally does.
如果点行的其它地方 通常事件会发生
If you tap somewhere else in the row, the row will do its normal thing.
但如果点的是这个i
But if you tap on the little I, instead,
它就会调用UITableViewDelegate协议的这个方法
it will call this method in the UI TableView Delegate Protocol,
叫tableView
called TableView
accessoryButtonTappedForRowWithIndexPath
Accessory Button Tap For Row with Index Path.
它是干什么的很明显
And it does exactly what you might think it tells you,
在小圆圈被点击时的索引路径
the index path of the little circle that was pressed.
这就是提供一些辅助信息的通常位置
So this is usually where you would provide some ancillary information.
这时不会发生点击行时发生的事件
You wouldn't do the main thing that the row does.
这时会发生一些同这一行相关的事情 但有所不同
You would go do something related to what's in that row, but different.
有问题
Question?
学生：你选出行[声音不清]
> So you pick out the row [inaudible]?
教授：是 问题是 我是不是能点击行或是那个小i
> Yes. So the question is, can I click on the row or on that little I?
答案是肯定的
And the answer is yes.
不同的事件会发生
And different things will happen.
点击行会segue跳转 或是调用
So clicking on the row would segue, or we'd call
前一张幻灯片上的didSelectRowAtIndexPath
that previous slide, did select row at index path,
点击i则会调用这个方法
clicking on the I we'd call this method.
委托的方法还有很多很多
There's lots and lots and lots of other delegate methods,
或许12个 甚至15个
probably over a dozen; maybe 15 of them.
它们也是用来处理各行 编辑各行
They also have to do with handling the rows -- editing of the rows
考虑到图形和动画这些方面
with a graphical -- how it happens graphically and animation of it.
不是关于数据 而是关于屏幕上的显示方式
Not as -- not the data that's involved, but just how it's going on on screen.
还有行的复制粘贴
And copying and pasting rows.
还有事物移动时的通知
And notifications for when things move.
各种东西
All kinds of stuff.
你们可以自己去查阅
So I'll leave that to you to go look up.
作业中 这些可能用不到
You won't probably need much -- any of that for your homework,
不过熟悉协议中的这些中西总是有好处的
but it's good to, you know, familiarize yourself with that protocol.
再来讲单元格的segue跳转
So let's talk about segueing from cells.
如何设置一个segue
So how do we set up a segue?
我们显然可以按Control键拖动
Well, we just control drag of course.
这是一个单元格 我可以从这个单元格Control拖动
So here's a cell, and I just control drag from that cell
到另外一个视图控制器
to some other view controller.
将这设为push segue
And let's say I make it a push segue.
我要把这个放到导航控制器中 它是push segue
I'm going to put this stuff in a navigation controller, and it's going to be a push segue.
这就创建了一个segue
And it creates a segue.
这里有趣的是 这是一个原型单元格
Now what's interesting about this, is that that's a prototype cell.
它会被复制很多很多次
It's going to be copied many, many times.
那么prepareForSegue时
So in prepare for segue,
我们怎么知道自己是从哪个单元格跳转来的呢
how are we going to know which cell we're segueing from?
如果我们要准备的是右边那个视图控制器
Because if we're going to prepare that view controller
也就是那个大的 空的 白的控制器
on the right -- that big, blank, white view controller --
我们就需要知道给它准备什么数据
we've got to know what data to prepare it with, right?
这取决于用户点击的是哪一行
Because it depends on which row they clicked on as to how we're going to prepare it.
我们在TableView的情况下看看prepareForSegue吧
So let's look at prepare for segue, in the case of a TableView.
这是一样的
So it's the same thing.
prepareForSegue: sender
Preparefor segue:sender.
不过sender参数
But now that sender argument --
之前我们一直忽略它 现在它就发挥作用了
which we've been ignoring so far -- matters.
sender的参数就是被点击的UITableViewCell
That sender argument is the UI TableView Cell that was clicked on.
有时 知道它的索引路径会很好
And sometimes it's really nice to know the index path of that thing.
你知道行和section 毕竟你是
You know? The row and section, because usually you're looking
根据行和section在模型中查找
up in your model by row and section.
这里有一个很重要的方法叫
And so there's this really important method called
indexPathForCell 在UITableView中
indexpathpercell in UI TableView,
它会告诉你给定单元格的索引路径
and it will tell you the index path for a given cell.
因此 在TableView的prepareForSegue: sender中
So we almost always, in the prepare for segue sender of TableViews
第一行几乎总是
do -- this first line is almost always
indexPath = self.tableView indexPathForCell
indexpath=self.Tableview indexpathforcell.
现在我们有了索引路径 我们可以在模型中查找
Now that we have index path, we can look it up in our model.
我们可以准备好segue跳转到的东西 这就好了
We can prepare the thing we're segueing to and off we go.
这方面有问题吗
Any questions about this?
否则就是常规的segue
Otherwise a normal segue.
好 转轮
Okay. Spinner.
记得在Imaginarium中
So remember in Imaginarium
我们在等待URL加载时让转轮在那旋转
we spin when we're waiting for the URL to load or whatever.
TableView的内容通常也需要从网络进行加载
TableView often the contents of the TableView are being loaded from the network.
这里也需要转动转轮
And we want to spin there too.
这样来让用户知道
We want to spin to let the user know
在其它线程中 在其它队列中
that in some other thread; on some other queue,
我们正下载表格中的数据
we're downloading data to fill up this table.
这在TableView中很容易做到
And it's really easy to do in TableView.
TableViewController
TableView Controller.
在TableViewController中很容易做到
It's easy to do in TableView Controller.
这不是TableView的部分 而是TableViewController的部分
It's not part of TableView. It's part of TableView Controller.
TableViewController有一个属性叫
TableView Controller has this property called
RefreshControl(刷新控制) 这是一个小转轮
"Refresh Control", and it's a little spinner.
只需要发送beginRefreshing(开始刷新) 旋转就会开始
And you just send, "Begin refreshing" to it and it will start spinning.
发送endRefreshing(终止刷新) 旋转就会停止
You say, "End refreshing" to it and it will stop spinning.
实际上 最酷的是 你还可以
And in fact, what's really cool is if you want, you can make it
在用户拉下TableView时 让转轮露出来
so the user can pull down on the TableView to reveal that spinner.
这将调用目标动作
And that will call a target action thing
这就能刷新表格 重新载入
and you can refresh your table; reload it.
换言之 你可以让用户控制刷新
So in other words you can let the user control the refreshing.
它是这样的
And so it would look like this:
这是我的TableViewController
So here's my TableView Controller there.
我还没有加入转轮
I haven't added the spinner yet.
看右边 在TableViewController的属性检查器中
If you look over on the right, in the attributes inspector for the TableView Controller,
中间这里有刷新
down towards the middle there there's refreshing.
我将它从禁用调到启用
And I'm switching it now from disabled to enabled.
在这里启用刷新
It says "Refreshing" is what it says on -- that's kind of covered there.
点击启用后 看文档大纲
And when I hit "Enabled", watch the document outline
文档大纲在左侧 这里会加一个东西
on the left -- okay, the document outline on the left, something's going to be added.
这是一个RefreshControl
Which is bloop -- a refresh control.
这时 它只出现在文档大纲
Now it only shows up in the document outline
因为它还不存在于任何地方 除非是在动画时
because it doesn't really exist anywhere except for when it's animating.
只有动画时 你才能看到它
So that's the only place that you can see it.
不过你可以从这里Control拖拽到TableViewController中
But you can control drag from it into your TableView Controller, right?
使用某种方法来分发一个线程
And put some method there that goes and forks off some thread
让另一个队列重载这张表格
on another queue to go reload this table.
最开始可以说beginRefreshing
And you just say, "Begin refreshing" at the beginning,
完成加载后 你回到主队列
and then once it's all finished loading, when you dispatch back
这时你可以说endRefreshing
to the main queue, you're going to say, "End refreshing."
有问题
Question?
学生：endRefreshing后 那个会消失吗
> End refreshing, does that thing disappear?
教授：会 endRefreshing后 转轮会被遮起来
> Yes. When you end refreshing, the little spinning thing, bloop, collapses back up.
TableView遮住它
So the TableView hides it.
beginRefreshing时 它又会重新出现
And then if you begin refreshing, bloop, it will show it again.
记住 用户下拉导致了这些信息的发送
And remember, user pulling down on it causes this message to be sent.
这里是刷新
Refresh in this case, right?
这里不过是目标动作
But it's just target action.
你想做什么都行
You can do anything you want.
这并不是必须的
You don't have to do it. If you don't wire --
如果你不Control拖动 那么下拉就没这个作用
control drag something, then pulling down won't do this.
如果TableView下 模型改变了会怎样
What if your model changes out from under your TableView?
TableView一直运行得很好 然后
So your TableView is running along fine, and then all
突然模型发生了重大变化 甚至完全变化
of a sudden the model changes in some fundamental way. Like it completely changes.
模型下载一组全新的信息
The model will download a completely new set of information.
你可以调用TableView中的reloadData(重载数据)方法
You can call this method in TableView called, "Reload data".
调用TableView时 它会调用多个section
And when you call reload data it's going to call number of sections.
section中的多个行 来得到表格…
Number of rows in section to get table --
cellForRowAtIndexPath
you know, cell for index -- cellforrowatindex path
这会不断发生 来重载整张表格
over and over and over again to reload the entire table.
这是一个任务繁重的操作
So this is a fairly heavyweight operation.
整张表格都需要重做
It's going to completely redo your whole table.
不过在整个模型发生变化时
But if your entire model changes,
这或许是合适的做法
this might be an appropriate thing to do.
这在我们今天的演示中肯定会发生
That's certainly going to happen in our demo that we're going to write today.
如果你知道模型中的变化比较细微
You can be -- if you know the changes in your model are finer tuned,
你可以调用reloadRowsAtIndexPaths
you can call methods like reloadrows atindexpaths.
只改变那些行
And only change those rows.
这是模型变化时重载UI的更加精细的做法
So it's kind of more fine-tuned reloading of your UI when your model changes.
你知道什么变化了
You know what changed.
还有其它一些方法
And there's some other methods too.
熟悉一下UITableView
So familiarize yourself with UI TableView
你会弄清你都能做些什么
you'll find out the kinds of things you can do.
UITableView本身之中也有好多种方法
There's dozens of other methods in UI TableView itself.
它是一个ScrollView
It's a ScrollView --
UITableView继承自UIScrollView
UI TableView inherits from ScrollView,
它有一些很好的方法 能够滚动到特定的行
so it's got some nice methods for scrolling to certain rows.
这能以一种很棒的动画方式发生
So it happens in a nice, animated way.
你可以设定header和footer
You can set those headers and footers that we talked
在最开始我就讲过这些
about at the very beginning; things like that.
你也应该熟悉UITableView
So you should familiarize yourself with UI TableView also
熟悉如何将它配置成你想要的样子
and all the things you can do to configure it the way you want.
你也可以在故事板中配置 在检查器中配置
And you can configure it also in the storyboards in the inspector there.
好 这是TableView
Okay. So that's it for TableView.
在继续推进之前 关于TableView有问题吗
Any questions on TableView before we go on?
好 下面我要讲通用应用
Okay. Now we're going to talk about universal applications.
通用应用指的是一个app同时适用于iPhone和iPad
A universal application is a single app that will run on iPhone and iPad.
一个app
A single app.
如何做到呢
And how do we do that?
如何让它适用于两者
How do we make it so it works on both?
这是两种完全不同的环境
Because they're kind of different idioms
iPad上有更大的屏幕空间
You know, you've got a lot more screen real estate in an iPad,
答案是 我们有两种单独的故事板
and the answer is, we have two separate storyboards.
通常 我们有相同的视图控制器
So we have the same view controllers, usually,
我们将它们以不同方式安排在另一个故事板中
and we just have different -- we arrange them in a different way in another storyboard.
我们有两种单独的故事板
So we have two separate storyboards.
它们并不共享任何…
And they don't really share anything --
虽然之间可以复制粘贴
although you can copy and paste things between them --
但没有办法把它们关联起来
you'll see me doing that -- but they don't really -- there's no way to like link them.
它们是单独的
They're really separate.
这是因为UI一般都会有非常不同的样子
And that's because the UI's want to generally look quite different.
功能是一样的
They're going to have the same functionality,
MVC相同 但会绘制在屏幕上的不同地方
so the same MVC's, but they're going to be drawn in different places on screen.
如何创建一个通用应用呢
How do you create a universal application?
在新建项目时 其中一个问题便是
Well, when you say, "Project New", one of the questions there is,
你想创建到什么平台 iPhone iPad还是通用
what platform do you want to create this for? iPhone? iPad? Or Universal?
点选通用 你就会得到两个故事板
And if you hit Universal, you'll get two storyboards and you're on your way.
如果你已经有了一个app 只适用于iPhone或iPad
If you have an existing app that's only iPhone or only iPad,
那项目设置就必须改变了
then you have to actually change our project settings.
这是这门课中我们首次关注项目设置
And this is the first time in this class we've looked at the project settings.
做法是点击app名
You get to them by clicking on the name of your app
在导航器的左上角
in the upper left-hand corner of the navigator there.
这里是Imaginarium
See where it says Imaginarium?
可以看到这些属性
And you'll see all these properties.
在general选项卡中
Well in the general tab --
看到顶部的general用蓝色标出了吧
see where it says general in blue there at the top?
这里有一些一般项目设置选项
There is some general project settings.
其中第二部分是部署信息
And the second one is deployment info.
关于在哪部署这个
Which is where you're going to deploy this.
这个app只适用于iPhone 因为在部署信息中它说
So this app is iPhone only because it says under deployment info,
部署目标7.0 设备iPhone
deployment target 7.0, devices, iPhone.
我要把设备从iPhone改为通用
So I'm going to change that devices iPhone right there to say universal.
改为通用后 它会提供选项
And when I change that to universal, it's going to offer
让我将已有故事板复制到新故事板
to copy my existing storyboard to the new storyboard.
这里是从iPhone复制到iPad
So in this case it's iPhone copy to an iPad.
我建议不复制
I recommend against this. I recommend saying, "Don't copy" here.
选不复制后
And if you say don't copy, then you'll have
你就需要自己创建故事板 做法是新文件
to make the storyboard yourself, and the way you do that is with new file.
这是Xcode创建一切新东西的方法
That's how we make everything anew in Xcode.
点创建新文件后
And when you go to new file, you go --
这时不选Objective-C类这些
instead of saying objective C class or something,
而是到下面找到用户界面 下面这里第三个
you go down towards this user interface -- it's the third one down right there.
看到了吗 然后在这里面 可以创建新视图或新窗口
See? And then inside there you can make a new view or a new window.
这里我们创建故事板 点选故事板
You're going to make a storyboard. So you click storyboard.
它会问你要怎样的
It's going to say what kind do you want?
我要一个iPad故事板
I want an iPad storyboard.
将它放到已有故事板的相同位置
Put it in the same place that your existing storyboard is,
这很有可能是一个叫作base.lproj的目录
which is probably going to be a directory called base.lproj
在主项目[声音不清]中
in the main project [inaudible].
总之 找到另一个故事板 放到一起
But just go find your other storyboard and put it in the same place.
你可以给它取一个很好的名称
You probably want to give it a good name like,
Main_iPad 或iPad 这之类
main underbar iPad or iPad or something like that.
然后放到一个好的组中
And then put it in a group -- a good group.
这里我放到了Imaginarium组中
You see down there I've put it in the Imaginarium group.
最上的组 顶层的组
The top group -- top level group.
现在 我有了iPad故事板
And then you -- now I have this iPad storyboard.
看到在我的文件导航器顶部
You see it at the top of my file navigator there
这里有Main_iPad.storyboard
in the main underbar iPad.storyboard.
这时 我需要在项目设置中
So now what I need to do is tell, in my project settings,
告诉Xcode这是我要iPad用的故事板
tell Xcode that that's the storyboard I want to use for iPad.
做法是点击屏幕中间这里的iPad
And I do that by clicking on where it says iPad there, in about the middle of the screen.
现在这里是iPhone 我要点iPad
Right now it's saying iPhone. So I'm going to click on iPad.
这就换了过来
It's going to switch over.
然后这里是我的界面文件
And then I'm going to say, my interface file --
主界面 设为Main_iPad.storyboard
main interface there -- is main iPad.storyboard.
这样一来 在iPad上运行时就都会用这个故事板了
Now it's going to use that storyboard whenever it runs on iPad.
如果忘了这一步 那么在iPad上运行时
If you forget to do this step, then when you're on an iPad,
程序会像一个巨大的iPhone
it's going to look like a gigantic iPhone.
界面将是一个
You know, the interface is just going
放大的iPhone版本
to be a gigantic version of your iPhone one.
你很快就会意识到 哦 我忘了这一步
So you'll quickly realize, oops I forgot this step.
我需要回头把这一步补上
I've got to go back and do this.
好 我们的app现在有了两个不同的故事板
Alright. So now we've got this app and it's got two different storyboards.
故事板为什么会不同呢
Why are storyboards different
两者之间又有哪些不同呢
and in what ways are they different between the two?
在iPad上 我们还有别的几种视图控制器
Well, on an iPad we have a couple of other view controllers
来将MVC显示在屏幕上
that we can use to put MVC's on screen.
一个是拆分视图(SplitView)
One is the split view.
拆分视图是将屏幕分成两个MVC
So split view is where we're going to split the screen up into two MVC's.
较窄的一个在左边 较大的一个在右边 看到了吗
Kind of a narrow one on the left and a bigger one on the right -- see that?
此外还有弹窗
And then also popovers.
弹窗是将MVC弹出到一个小矩形中
Popovers are where we're going to pop an MVC up in a little rectangle.
看到白色区域内的方程式了吗
So that little white area where the equations are there?
这就是一个小型TableView弹出到弹窗中
That is a little TableView that's popping up in a popover.
我们将讲到拆分视图 弹窗及其工作方式
So we're going to talk about split view and popover and how those work.
不过首先 在代码中
But first in your code,
如何知道你是在iPad上
how can you tell you're on an iPad
然后在代码中做点不同的事
so that you can do something different in your code?
代码基础是共用的
Because you have this shared code base.
唯一的不同是故事板
The only thing that's different is the storyboards.
有时 你需要分辨是不是在iPad上
So sometimes you want to tell if you're on an iPad.
这就是做法 好
Well, that's the way to do it, okay.
我建议在检查是否在iPad上之前
I kind of recommend thinking about if there are other things
先考虑检查一下别的东西
to check first before checking if you're on an iPad.
例如 是否处在SplitView控制器中
Like are you in a SplitView controller?
当前MVC是否处在SplitView控制器中
Is your current MVC in a SplitView controller
我会告诉你们如何检查这个
and I'm going to show you how you can check that.
我要通信的MVC 或是我自己 我的MVC
Or is the MVC that I want to talk to, or is myself -- my MVC --
现在是否在屏幕上
on screen right now?
要知道在iPad上 它可能在屏幕上 因为空间更大
Because on iPad it might be on screen because there's more room
更多MVC可以待在屏幕上
for -- and more MVC's to be on screen.
在iPhone上时 则可能不在屏幕上
Whereas on iPhone might not be on screen.
这里有些东西需要先检查
So there's something to check first
在检查是否处在iPad上时 先检查是否在屏幕上
before checking am I on iPad, just check am I on screen?
或 我是否处在SplitView控制器中
Or am I in a SplitView controller?
或 我是否处在弹窗中
Or am I in a popover?
我们等下就会展示如何检查
So we're going to show how to check -- or how to check if you're
是否处在SplitView控制器中
in a SplitView controller in a second here.
SplitView控制器是这样的
So here's what a SplitView controller looks like.
左边的视图有个名称 叫作master(主要)
We have a name for the left view, we call that the master.
右边的视图我们称之为detail(明细)
And the right view we call the detail.
这是因为两者之间通常有一个主要/明细关系
And that's usually because there's a master/detail relationship between the two.
master中发生的情况通常会决定
With changing in the master usually is affecting what's
detail中发生的情况
driving; what's happening in the detail.
左边是SplitViewController的横屏模式
So here's one in landscape mode and another one
右边则是竖屏模式
in portrait mode of the SplitView controller.
这是计算器 它有两个MVC
This is a calculator, so it's got two MVC's.
一个是计算器键盘MVC
Kind of a calculator keypad MVC and then a calculator graph --
另一个是绘图MVC
or graphing MVC that knows how to graph things.
这是一个绘图计算器
So it's like a graphing calculator.
SplitViewController位于顶级
The SplitView controller is designed to be at the top level.
因此 不要把它放到导航控制器
So don't put a SplitView controller inside a navigation
或是选项卡栏控制器内 千万不要
controller or inside a Tab Bar controller. Just don't do it.
它不是这样工作的
It's not really designed to work that way.
你可以把这些放到它里面 哪一侧都行
You can put those things inside it, in either side,
但不要把SplitView放到它们里面
but don't put the SplitView inside them.
要在故事板中添加一个非常简单
It's very simple to add one to your storyboard.
你只需要把它拖出来 然后它会给你
You just drag it out and then it's going to give you a couple
一个master和一个detail
of -- it's going to give you a master and a detail,
这个你几乎总会删掉
which you're going to delete almost all the time.
然后你control拖动到你的master和detail
And then you just control drag to your master and control drag to your detail.
就像选项卡栏控制器一样 它会以相同方式关联起来
Just like a Tab Bar controller, it gets hooked up the same, exact way.
在代码中 你希望能够访问master和detail
In your code, you want to be able to access the master and the detail.
这方面你需要知道两个属性
And there's two properties you need to know about that.
一个属性在UIViewController中 叫splitViewController
One is the property in UI View Controller, called SplitView Controller.
如果你发送splitViewController getter
So if you send SplitView Controller, getter,
给任何UIViewController
to any UI View Controller,
它会返回它所处的SplitViewController
it will return what SplitView Controller it's in.
如果它处在一个SplitViewController中的话
If it's in one. Anywhere in it.
如果不在SplitViewController中 它会返回nil
If it's not in it, it will return nil.
这是一个很好的检查标准
So this is a good thing to check if you have conditional code
如果你有条件代码 在iPad和iPhone上按不同方式工作
that works one way in an iPad and one way on an iPhone.
你可以检查是否处在SplitViewController中
Is whether you're in a SplitView Controller or not.
iPad界面是否建立在SplitViewController之上
If your iPad interface is built on a SplitView Controller.
知道处在什么SplitViewController中后
Now, once you find out what SplitView Controller you're in,
你可以问SplitViewController
you can ask the SplitView Controller,
请告诉我master和detail
please tell me the detail -- the master and the detail.
做法是通过这个数组
And the way you do that is with this array
在UISplitViewController中 叫viewControllers
in UI SplitView Controller called, "View Controllers".
这个数组总有两个项目在里面 0是master
And that array always has two items in it; 0 is the master.
1是detail
1 is the detail.
例如 如果我有一个master VC
So for example, if I had a master VC
它想弄清在相同的SplitViewController中 detail是什么
and it wanted to find out what the detail was in the same SplitView Controller it's in,
它会说 self.splitViewController.viewControllers[1]
it would say, self.splitviewcontroller.viewcontrollersub1.
如果不处在SplitViewController中 这会返回nil
And that would return nil if it's not in a SplitView Controller at all.
处在SplitViewController中时 它会返回detail
And if it is a SplitView Controller, it would return the detail.
能理解吗
Make sense?
SplitViewController有一点很有趣
And so one thing that's kind of interesting about SplitView Controller,
同TableView数据源类似 也就是
similar to the TableView datasource is it requires its
它需要SplitViewControllerDelegate得到设定
SplitView Controller delegate to be set.
为什么这个需要设定呢
And why is this that it's required to be set?
答案是竖屏模式
The answer is portrait mode.
后面我会在幻灯片中展示一些图片
And I'm going to show you this in some pictures in the next couple of slides.
为什么需要委托
Why you need the delegate.
委托很烦人
The delegate is annoying.
这是iOS最烦人的委托
It's the most annoying delegate in all of IOS.
首先 它需要很早设定
Firstly it has to be set very early.
也就是在awakeFromNib中
Meaning in away from NIB.
你不能等到viewDidLoad
You can't wait till view did load
来设定SplitViewController的委托
to set your SplitView Controller's delegate.
这很烦人
So that's annoying.
然后 在viewDidLoad发生之前 它就开始
Second of all, it starts calling the delegate methods
从SplitViewController调用委托方法
from the SplitView Controller before view did load happens.
调用委托方法时 什么outlet都还没有设定
So none of your outlets are set while its calling its delegate methods.
这很烦人
So that's annoying.
所以说 SplitViewControllerDelegate很难打交道
So it's very difficult to deal with the SplitView Controller delegate.
幸运的是 它只有一个很简单的职责
Fortunately it only has one, simple responsibility.
也就是控制master和detail何时出现
Which is to control when the master and the detail appear
在横屏模式和竖屏模式中
in the landscape versus portrait modes.
实现这个方法
So in -- so you implement this method.
这个方法是通往SplitViewControllerDelegate的门路
This is kind of the gateway SplitView Controller delegate
叫作splitViewController: shouldHideViewController:
method called SplitViewcontroller shouldhighviewcontroller
inOrientation:
inorientation.
它会在横屏或竖屏模式中问你 是否应该隐藏master
And it's going to ask you in landscape or in portrait, should I hide the master?
如果返回NO 意思是说从不
Now if you return no, that means never.
这意味着master和detail将一直在屏幕上
That means the master and the detail will be on screen
无论是在横屏模式还是竖屏模式中
in both the landscape mode and the portrait mode.
不过这意味着 竖屏模式中
But that does mean that in portrait mode
detail会又高又细
the details can be kind of tall and skinny.
master总是又高又细的
The master's always tall and skinny.
但detail则高细得有些异常
The details can be kind of unusually tall and skinny.
不过有时在UI中 这样做也行
But sometimes UI this makes sense.
除NO以外 另一种返回方式是说 只在竖屏中
Another thing to return, besides no, is to say only in portrait.
只在竖屏中隐藏master
So only hide the master in portrait.
这样在横屏中 你就能看到master
So now in landscape you'll see the master in the detail;
而竖屏中则看不到
in portrait you won't.
这里重要的是 如果我处在竖屏
But the important thing about this is, if I'm in portrait,
如何获得master呢
how do I get at the master?
答案是 它会给你一个栏按钮
And the answer is, it's going to give you a little bar button.
左上角那个蓝色的就是
You see that little blue bar button up in the corner there?
有点看不清 我用黄色对话框指向了它
You can barely see it. It's being pointed to by that yellow call out?
点击这个按钮 master就会滑出
That button, if I click on it, it's going to slide the master out.
看到了吗 master滑出
See? Slides the master out.
点击detail中其它地方 它会消失
If I click anywhere else in the detail it goes away.
再次点击按钮 master再次滑出
Click on the button again it slides the master out.
这就是在竖屏模式中访问master的方式
So that's how I can get at the master even in portrait mode.
不过这个按钮需要放到某个地方
But I have to put that button somewhere.
很不幸 这是我的职责
That's my responsibility unfortunately.
我需要在所有outlet设定之前搞定
And I have to do it before all my outlets are set,
这让我有点难办
so that makes it difficult to do.
怎么做的呢
But how would that work?
把按钮放到这里
Okay, so to put that button there,
SplitViewController会发送给你…
the SplitView Controller is going to send you --
顺便说下 如果你不实现委托
oh by the way, if you don't implement the delegate,
在竖屏模式中
what's going to happen is in portrait mode, there's not going
按钮不会存在 用户无法访问master
to be a button there and so the user won't be able to get at the master.
用户显然不希望这样
And that's a little frustrating for users.
你可以说 换成横屏不就行了
You could just say, well just switch the landscape.
那就有master了
You could have the master back.
也许这也行
Ehh, well maybe that's okay.
我不知道
I don't know.
我认为这样不是很好
I don't think it's that great.
哪怕是在竖屏模式中 用户也会指望访问master
Users would expect to be able to get at the master, even from portrait mode.
如果不实现委托 这里就不会有按钮
So if you don't do the delegate, you won't have a button there.
用户无法访问master
People won't be able to get at the master.
在这里放上按钮的是另一个SplitView委托方法
So the way you put the button there is, another SplitView delegate method.
willHideViewController: withBarButtonItem:
Willhideview controller withbar buttonitem.
这里说的是 我要隐藏master
And what's that's saying is, I'm going to hide the master.
这里有一个栏按钮要放到屏幕上的某个地方
Here's a bar button to put somewhere on the screen,
用户点击它时 master就会滑动出来
that when the user clicks it, it will slide back.
这是一种很简单的实现方法
So here's a simple way to implement it.
将detail放到导航控制器中
Put your detail in a navigation controller.
You put your detail in a navigation controller.
然后你可以设定左侧的栏按钮项目为那个栏按钮
Then you can set the left bar button item to be that bar button.
这种做法很酷
What's cool about this way is
因为左侧栏按钮项目的设定
that you can set the left bar button item by setting it
可以通过设定在UI视图控制器的导航项目上得到
on the navigation item of a UI view controller.
这意味着 哪怕你还没设置好
Which means even though you're not set up yet;
还没有任何outlet
you don't have any outlets,
你就可以把栏按钮放到那里
you can just put that bar button in there
无论任何时候 只要视图出现在导航控制器中
and when the view appears in a navigation controller at any time,
它就会使用这个左侧栏按钮项目
it's going to use that left bar button item.
这就是将它放到左上角的方式
So that's how you put it in the left [inaudible].
这是一种很巧妙的做法
So this is kind of a tricky way to do it.
让这很容易实现
To make this really easy to implement.
我推荐它 它是一个很棒的技巧
I kind of recommend it. It's a good trick.
没什么不好的
There's nothing bad about it.
唯一的问题在于 你不会希望
The only thing that's bad about it is you would never want
导航同时在master和detail中进行
to have navigation going on both in your master and your detail.
哪怕你的detail处在导航控制器中
So even though your detail's in a navigation controller,
你也不要允许任何实际导航发生
don't allow any actual navigation there.
你只是希望用它找个地方放这个栏按钮
You're only using it to have a place to put this bar
并在上面写一个标题
and get a title at the top.
我们会在演示中做这个
We'll do that in the demo.
类似地 切换回横屏模式后
And then similarly, when it switches back to landscape,
它会说 你现在可以把栏按钮去掉了
then it's going to say, okay you can take that bar button away now.
因为master在横屏模式中总是可见的
Because the master is visible always in landscape.
这就是这了
So that's it.
这是SplitView中的三个方法
Those are the three SplitView ones.
这些幻灯片可以供你们复习
These slides are here for you to review.
这个委托比较难
This is a difficult delegate,
不过要让SplitView正常工作
but to make SplitView really work right,
很不幸 你需要实现这三个方法
unfortunately you have to implement these three methods.
好 在master变化时 更新detail
Okay. So updating the detail when the master changes.
这在SplitView中非常基础
That's a fundamental thing about what happens in SplitView.
如何做到呢
How do you do that?
detail和mater同时处在屏幕上
Because the detail and the master are both on screen at the same time.
当有人在master中点击时 detail如何更新
How are we going to update the detail when someone clicks in the master basically.
有两种做法 一是目标动作
And there's two choices. One is target action.
让master有一个目标动作方法到它自身
So just have your master have a target action method to itself.
它有了这个目标动作后
And when it gets that target action it's going
就会去找detail 并进行更新
to go find its detail and update the detail.
同prepareForSegue的做法基本一样
Basically do the same thing it would do in preparing for segue.
设定detail中必要的东西
Just set whatever's necessary on that detail.
我们在演示中会做这个
That's what we're going to do in our demo.
当然 如果master中是TableView
Of course if it's a TableView in master,
你就需要使用那个didSelectRowAtIndexPath
you have to use that didselectrow atindexpath.
这是TableView的目标动作
That's target action for TableView.
但是 如果只是mster中的一个按钮
But if it were just a button in your master
就像计算器那样 你可以点一个按钮让它显示图像
like that calculator thing, you could just click a button that says show the graph,
这就是普通的目标动作 它会做这样的事情
it could just be normal target action and it would do something like this.
找detail 然后更新之
Find the detail and go update it.
第二种方式是使用segue
The second way is with a segue.
这被称作替换segue
It's called a replace segue.
这个segue替换了整个detail视图
This segue replaces the entire detail view.
完全替换了它
Completely replaces it.
这个很讨厌 因为所有那些委托方法
This one's kind of annoying because of all of those delegate methods.
因为它会替换掉整个视图 包括
Because it's going to replace the entire view including the
导航控制器以及那个小按钮
navigation controller with the little button.
segue到一个新的 你需要把按钮弄出来
So you segue to a new one, and now you've got to somehow get
并将它放到新的里面
that button out of there and put it back into the new one.
这很麻烦
It's quite a pain in the neck.
因此SplitViewController中 我们很少使用替换segue
So we don't really use the replace segue that much in the SplitView Controller.
在master总可见的情况下 这还很好
It's pretty good in the ones where the master is always visible.
但在master隐藏的情况下
But if we're ever doing the one where the master hides
上面有个按钮 让按钮维持在上面那里很麻烦
and we put a button up there, it's a pain to keep that button up there when it's
替换segue会持续不断地替换掉
constantly replacing the segue on the right side.
记得吧 segue总会给出视图控制器的新版本
Remember by the way, segues always give you new versions of view controllers.
在做Imaginarium时
So when we were doing Imaginarium,
每次我们点击新的花 水母或是别的什么
every time we'd click on a new flower or jellyfish or whatever,
它会使用一个全新的视图控制器实例
it would push to a brand new instance of view controller.
segue总是新实例
segues are always new instances.
它们从不再利用一个视图控制器
They're never reusing, ever a view controller.
这对segue是根本的
That's fundamental to a segue.
它总会给出新实例
It gives you a new instance all the time.
这里这将是一个新实例 它会替换掉detail
So here it would be a new instance and it would replace the detail.
这叫替换segue
It's called a replace segue.
要做这个 你只需要control拖动
And to do that you just control drag.
类型不选push 而选replace
And the kind, it's instead of being push, you pick replace.
这只在SplitView中有效
It will only work when you're doing it inside of a SplitView.
iPad要讲的最后一点是弹窗
Last thing we're going to talk about on iPad is popovers.
弹窗是这样的
So this is what a popover looks like.
这是一个TableView 弹窗内有一些方程式
Okay. There's the little TableView with the equations in it inside a popover.
弹窗控制器PopoverController类并不是UIViewController
And popover controller, the class, is actually not a UI View Controller.
PopoverController是一个NSObject
Popover controller is an NS object.
它的作用是控制另一个视图控制器 弹出到屏幕上
But what it does is it controls another view controller popping up on screen.
做法是通过这个属性 contentViewController
And it does that with this property content view controller.
你在UIPopoverController上设置这个
You set that on the UI popover controller.
通常 你control拖动它到故事板
Usually you control drag it into storyboard.
因此 这个属性几乎不需要直接设置
So you almost never actually set this property directly.
设定这个segue后
And when you set it, that segue.
当用户点击触发segue的东西时
When the person clicks on it -- the thing that's going to cause the segue --
你会得到prepareForSegue 因为这是一个segue
you're going to get prepare for segue because it's a segue.
不过这里有一点很特殊
But there's a special thing there,
也就是 你将得到的segue将是
which is that the segue you get is going to be a subclass
UIStoryboardPopoverSegue的子类
of UI storyboard popover segue.
你可以检查这些类 如果是
And so you can check this kind of class, and if it is,
你可以让segue给你弹窗控制器
you can ask the segue, give me the popover controller --
UIPopoverController
UI popover controller --
控制这个要弹出的窗口
that controls this thing that's going to popover.
不过大多数弹窗
But mostly popovers are just a matter
只是去找你要弹出的视图控制器
of finding the view controller that you want to pop up.
control拖动到其中
Control drag into it.
设定弹窗segue的类型 然后释放
Setting the type of segue to be popover, and letting it go.
为segue做好准备 然后就好了
And just prepare for segue and off you go.
这是很普通的segue
It's a normal segue.
重复一次 这是一个segue
And again, it's a segue so the
因此要放到弹窗内的视图控制器会实例化
view controller that's going to be put inside the popover is instantiated.
全新的一个 使用故事板中的内容
A brand new one; using whatever's in storyboard.
弹窗在故事板中很容易
So popovers are actually really easy in the storyboard.
只需要control拖动 这就好了
You just control, drag, boom you're done.
有时 你都不需要做这些事
And sometimes you don't even need to do this business
为segue做准备 因为你不需要同弹窗控制器对话
and prepare for segue because you don't need to talk to the popover controller.
你只需要同你要segue到的东西对话
You just need to talk to the thing you're segueing to.
设定带有方程的TableView
Set up that TableView with the equations in it --
y=x cosx 或是别的什么
y=x cosine x or whatever was in there.
你只需要设置这些 你都不需要弹窗控制器
You just need to set that up. So you don't even need the popover controller.
你只需要同弹窗内的东西展开对话
You just need to talk directly to the thing inside the popover.
用户要取消弹窗
The user dismisses a popover
只需要点击外面任何地方
by just touching anywhere outside of it.
点击外面任何地方 弹窗就会消失
If they touch outside of it the popover dismisses.
这里有一个例外 如果用户点击外面
You can -- there is an exception if they touch outside
但点击的是弹窗控制器中这个视图数组中的视图
of it, but they touch on a view that's in this array of views in the popover controller,
这就会出现例外
those are like exceptions.
这时 弹窗就不会消失
Those won't cause it to dismiss.
一个很烦人的情况是工具栏
One thing -- annoying case of this is a toolbar.
整个工具栏处在passthroughViews中
The entire toolbar is in the passthroughViews.
如果从工具栏上点击按钮弹出一个窗口
So if you bring up a popover from a button in a toolbar,
然后用户点击工具栏上别的地方
then if the user clicks anywhere else in the toolbar --
例如另一个按钮 这个弹窗不会消失
like on another button -- it won't dismiss that popover.
为什么要这样设计 我不知道
Why they decided to do that, I do not know.
反正 这个passthroughViews就是这样
But that's what this pass through views thing is.
这可能会很烦人
It can be annoying.
你也可以自己设置
But you can set it yourself too.
你可以说 如果点击这里 我不希望弹窗消失
You can say, well if they click over here, I don't want to dismiss that popover.
你也可以在代码中让弹窗消失
You can dismiss popovers from code by just saying,
使用dismissPopoverAnimated 在UIPopoverController中
dismisspopover animated, in UI Popover Controller,
这样它就会消失
and that will dismiss it.
你还可以弄清用户是否让它消失
And you can find out if the user dismissed it using
使用popoverControllerDidDismissPopover
popovercontroller diddismiss thispopover.
这是一个UIPopoverControllerDelegate方法
This is a UI Popover Controller delegate method.
如果UIPopoverController有一个委托 而且你设置了
So if UI Popover Controller has a delegate, and if you set that delegate
你就会在用户取消弹窗时获得这个信息
you'll get this message when the user dismisses the popover.
通常 你不需要弄清这个 不过有时这个可能会有用
You usually don't need to find this out, but sometimes you want to know.
这是弹窗
So that's popovers.
这周的作业中我不要求你们使用弹窗
We're not going to -- I'm not going to ask you to do popovers in your homework this week.
我会把它布置到下周 它也不在我的演示中
I'll try to fit it into next weeks, and it's not in my demo either.
弹窗这个可能会有些模糊
So popovers are going to remain probably a little bit, you know,
直到我们进行演示
fuzzy to you until we do a demo.
这是演示
So here is the demo.
名字叫Shutterbug(摄影迷)
It's called Shutter Bug.
我将有一个TableView
And what it's going to be is I'm going to have a TableView full
其中有一两百张Flickr上最新发布的照片
of a list of a couple of hundred of the most recently posted photos on Flickr.
我会访问Flickr
So I'm going to query Flickr with, you know, URL.
并获得这些信息
Go out there and query Flickr and get this information.
然后用信息填满TableView
Load up the TableView with it,
点击它时
and when you click on it we'll use
我们会用Imaginarium的图像视图控制器来显示照片
our image view controller from Imaginarium to display the photo.
然后我会在iPhone和iPad上这样做
And then I'm going to do that on the iPhone; and I'm going to do it on iPad as well.
演示就是这样了
So that's what the demo's going to be.
这里你们会看到很多东西
And you'll see a lot of stuff here.
好 把这个挪开
Alright. So let's get this out of the way.
这是接下来的一些东西
I'll show you the coming attractions here.
作业今天布置 一周后交
Your homework that's going out today is due in a week --
下周三 关于所有这些东西
next Wednesday -- it's about all this stuff.
周五 我们还是有斯坦福专用课外辅导
Again, Friday we have the Stanford only section.
下周 我们还会谈到Core Data
And then next week we'll be covering core data.
或许我们还会谈到多任务API
And maybe we'll get to some multitasking API as well.
好 关掉这个
Alright. Let's close that.
我们要在Xcode中创建一个新项目
We're going to create a new -- oops -- new project here in Xcode.
名字叫Shutterbug
I'm going to call it Shutter Bug.
它将是通用的
And it's going to be universal.
不只用于iPhone 而是通用的
So I'm not making it iPhone only; I'm going to make it universal.
我会得到两个故事板 点击这个
So I'm going to get two storyboards out of this when I click this.
这些东西还是放到老地方
We'll put it in at the same place we always put everything.
这里可以看到 两个故事板
So here it is, and you can see two storyboards.
这里有一个iPhone故事板
There's an iPhone storyboard right here.
这里有一个iPad故事板
And here's an iPad storyboard.
这两个中间我什么都不想要
And so I don't really want anything in either of these,
这里有一个巨大的视图 我打算删掉
so I've got this gigantic view here, so I'm just going to delete that.
iPhone也是一样 把这个删掉
And same thing iPhone. I've got this one right here, I'm going to delete that.
这两个我都打算从完全空白的故事板开始
So I'm going to start with completely blank storyboards in both.
首先建立iPhone这个
And we'll build the iPhone one first.
然后再转到iPad
Then we'll switch over to the iPad.
这是一个基于TableView的app
So this is going to be a TableView-based app.
我只需要选一个TableView 然后拖出来
So I'm just going to pick up a TableView out of here and drag it out.
这是我的TableView
So here's my TableView.
显然 我要把它的类
Of course I'm going to want to set its class
设置为UITableViewController的子类
to be some subclass of UI TableView Controller.
我们照这样来做
So let's go do that. Let's make that.
这是一个类
Alright. It's a class.
它是UITableViewController的子类
It's going to be a subclass of UI TableView Controller.
这个我打算取名为FlickrPhotosTVC
I'm going to call this thing Flickr Photos TVC --
TVC表示表格视图控制器
for TableView Controller. Because that's what it's going to do.
这是一个显示Flickr照片的表格视图控制器
It's going to be a TableView Controller that shows Flickr photos.
把它放到标准位置
And I'll put it in the normal places.
有了
Here we go.
到这里 将其设为当前的类
Let's go over here and we'll set that to be our class for now.
看这个类 其中有所有这些代码
And so now, if I look at this class, this is going to have all of my code in it.
这里有很多东西
Now it comes with a lot of stuff.
有视图控制器生命周期的东西
Here's my view controller lifecycle stuff that it has,
我要把这些删除掉
I'm going to get rid of that.
它有这个表格视图数据源的东西
It comes with this TableView datasource stuff --
顺便说下 我喜欢改变这里的pragma
by the way I like to change this pragma
让它像这样
to be -- to look like this.
这样我更容易看
It's a little easier for me to see.
这将是TableViewDatasource方法
And this is the -- going to be the TableView datasource
认识这三个吧
method. Do you recognize those three?
section数目
Number of sections?
行数
Number of rows?
我们会实现这些
So we're going to implement those.
注释掉的内容 为编辑表格提供了很多东西
Comment it out down here it gives you a lot of stuff for editing the table.
四处移动 诸如此类
Moving things around, stuff like that.
今天我不打算讲这些 你可以闲暇时看看
We're not going to cover any of that today. You can review at your leisure.
然后显然是导航 这是prepareForSegue
And then of course navigation, which is prepare for segue,
后面我们会做这个
we are going to do that a little bit later.
这里我们有了一个新类
So we have a new class here.
我们谈谈它的公共API
Let's talk about its public API.
这个的公共API很简单
And this one's going to have easy public API.
这是一个strong NSArray 我们称之为photos
Which is a strong NS array, which we'll call photos.
这将是Flickr照片NSDictionary中的
And this is going to be of Flickr photo NS dictionaries.
这些是我从Flickr下载的字典
So these are going to be dictionaries that I'm going to download from Flickr.
在Flickr上 这些字典有关于照片的信息
And these dictionaries have information about photos that are on Flickr.
这里不过是这些
So that's all these are.
字典 带有一系列关于照片的键和值
Dictionaries with a bunch of keys and values in there about photos.
并不是实际的图像数据
Not the actual image data --
那些需要单独取用
I'll have to fetch that separately.
这里只是关于照片的信息
But just information about it.
有一点我要确保自己做了 也就是模型变化时
And one thing I really want to make sure that I do, is that when my model changes --
当有人设置照片… 哦…
so someone sets the photos -- oops --
重来一次
I do this again -- this is doing this again --
如果有人设置了这个照片数组
so if someone sets this array of photos --
那么我就要确保我的TableView更新了
then I'm going to make sure that I update my TableView.
是叫这个吧 重载[声音不清]时 对
Is that what it's called when you reload [inaudible] yeah.
只要模型发生变化 我就需要
And that's just -- any time a model changes, obviously I want
重载表格中的数据
to reload my data in my table.
这很好理解
That makes sense.
我如何设置这个呢
Now how am I going to set this?
如何调用setPhotos
How am I going to call set photos?
如何获得这些Flickr数据
How am I going to get this Flickr data?
代码放到哪
Where am I going to put that code?
我不打算把代码放到这个类中
Well I don't actually want to put that in this class.
因为我希望这个类是通用的
Because I want this class to be a generic,
Flickr照片浏览类
Flickr photo viewing class.
我不希望它只能针对特定的一系列照片
I don't want it to be specific to any particular set of photos,
我打算为此建立一个具体的子类
so I'm going to make a concrete subclass of this --
这不是一个抽象类 因为它能独自工作
okay, so this is not really an abstract class because it kind of works on its own.
我打算建立一个具体的子类
But I'm going to make a -- essentially like a concrete subclass of it.
它是FlickrPhotosTVC的一个子类
It's a subclass of Flickr photos TVC.
起名为JustPostedFlikrPhotosTVC
And I'm going to call it, justposted flikrphotostvc.
它是FlickrPhotosTVC的一个子类
So it's going to be a subclass of that and it's going
用于显示刚刚发布的那些
to show me the ones that have just been posted.
我们创建这个 到这里
So let's create that in here.
我们得到了这个新的
So we have this new one here.
它只需要调用self.photos
And it's just -- all it's going to do is call self.photos
来设置这里的模型
to set this model right here.
在故事板中 我们换个类
So in our storyboard, let's change our class here.
我们将从FlickrPhotosTVC
Instead of being flickrsphotostvc,
切换到JustPostedFlikrPhotosTVC
I'm going to change this to be justpostedflickr photostvc.
这就会显示刚刚发布的那些
So now that's going to show my just posted ones.
刚刚发布的这些如何实现呢
So what about the implementation of this just posted?
很简单
It's really easy.
我只需要在viewDidLoad中
I just in my view id load --
super viewDidLoad
super viewDidLoad,
我要调用self fetchPhotos
I'm just going to call selffetchphotos.
然后这里创建fetchPhotos方法
And then we'll make a fetchphotos method here.
这里写 self.photos=什么东西
And I'm just going to say self.photos= something.
我将在这里取回照片
That's -- I'm going to get my photos here.
这里有什么问题
Alright, what's the problem here?
根类 这很奇怪
Root class -- hmm that's weird.
哦 奇怪了
Oh. Strange.
FlickrPhotosTVC
Flickrphotostvc.
好 我不知道为什么没有加上这个
Okay. I'm not sure why it didn't add that.
好 就是这样了 这很好
Okay. So there we go. Alright so that's good.
在这里 我们需要
So that's where -- so in here is where we're going to have to go
去取Flickr照片
out to make a fetch to Flickr and do that.
我们来写这段代码
So let's go ahead and write that code.
很简单
Pretty straight forward.
我们需要一点辅助代码
One thing we're going to need though is a little bit
帮助我们取用Flickr数据
of helper code to help us with those Flickr fetches.
为了作业需要 这个提供给你们
And I've provided this to you for your homework.
在这里
Here it is right here.
这是Flickr取用代码
This Flickr fetching code.
我们到这里来
Let's go over here to this.
拖进来 简单看一下
We can drag this in. We'll take a brief look at this.
复制进来
I'm going to copy it in.
好 看这个Flickr取用器
Alright. So if you look at this Flickr fetcher,
它有这个API 提供这些类方法
it has this API right here that provides these class methods
这里有一些URL 你能从中取用Flickr信息
with some URLs that you can fetch information from Flickr.
例如 我们会考虑最新地理参考的照片
So we're going to do, for example, recent georeferenced photos.
作业中 你们需要考虑顶级位置
For your homework you're going to want to do top places.
因为作业中 我要求你们从Flickr中展示位置
Because in your homework you're going to be asked to show places from Flickr.
而这里我只显示照片
And I'm just going to be showing only photos.
我们打算使用这些URL来取回信息
So we're going to use those URLs to do some fetching.
我需要import FlickrFetcher.h 像这样
So I better import flickrfetcher.h so I can do that.
这个如何工作呢
And how does this work?
获得URL 用此来获得刚发布的照片
Well, let's get the URL that we're going to use to get those just posted photos
通过这个FlickrFetcher
from this Flickrfetcher thing,
URL
URL.
我要这个 最近照片
And so I want this one, recent photos.
这样我就有了一个URL 我要获取数据
So now I have a URL. I need to get that data.
这是NSData
So that's NSdata.
从Flickr取回的数据 格式是JSON
Now the data that comes back from Flickr comes back in a format called JSON.
知道JSON的请举手
Raise your hand if you know what JSON is.
几乎所有人都知道JSON
Okay, so almost everyone knows what JSON is.
我不想要JSON格式 但我别无选择
So I don't want it in JSON, but that's my only choice.
我要从JSON中获得结果
So I'm going to get those results in JSON
我可以说 NSData dataWithContentsOfURL
by saying NSdata -- datawithcontentsofurl.
同之前… dataWithContentsOfURL
Same thing we used datawith contentsofurl.
同之前的做法一样
Same thing we did before.
不过我不想要JSON格式
But I don't want them in JSON format.
我希望格式是数组和字典
Really the format that I want them in is arrays and dictionaries.
比起JSON 这些显然更好处理
That's a much nicer format for us to deal with than JSON.
JSON很像数组和字典 不过并不完全一样
JSON is like arrays in dictionaries but not exactly the same.
幸运的是 iOS中有一种方式能够做到
Luckily, there is a way in IOS to do that.
我们将把这些转化为propertyListResults
So we'll change that to basically property list results.
将JSON格式转化为属性列表
To turn a JSON thing into a property list,
这是JSON… 叫什么来着
and that's with the [inaudible] JSON -- what's called again?
NSJSONSerialization
NSjsonserialization.
方法叫作JsonObjectWithData
And the method is called jsonobjectwithdata.
你给它JSON数据
You give it the JSON data.
选项 0 这些你可以自己去查
Options. We'll say 0 -- you can look those up if you want.
它可以返回NS错误
And it will return an error and that's -- you know, NS error,
不过我们不打算检查 便于演示
but we're not going to check for errors because it's a demo.
这样 我就有了字典格式
And so now I have this stuff in dictionary format.
在继续推进之前 我们先来看看log
So before we go any further, let's just log this.
"Flickr results = %@", propertyListResults
Flickrresults =%@property listresults.
通过log 我们可以看到它是怎样的
So I'm just going to log this so we can take a look and see what this looks like.
运行一下 现在在UI中 它还什么都做不了
So let's just run this. It's not going to do anything in our UI yet,
不过它会记录这次数据取回的日志
but hopefully it will log this particular fetch of the fetchworks.
哦 似乎没能正常工作
So -- oh, well, no that's not working.
糟糕 好吧 让我这样
Well, that's not good -- oh that's okay, let's do this.
到这里
Alright let's do it here.
因为iPad还没有设置 而它想到iPad上运行
Because we haven't done our iPad one, it's trying to run it on an iPad.
我们用模拟器来试下
So we're just going to run it on the simulator here.
把模拟器弄小点
So much for our little simulator.
我们不打算看UI中的情况
Okay we're not actually going to be looking at anything in UI.
它不过是在取回数据 信息显示在这里
So it's doing this fetch, and here's the information right here.
放大一些 这样你们就能看到
Let's go ahead and make it big so you can see it.
可以看到 这是一个字典
And you can see that it's a dictionary.
这个格式就是作为字典进行的记录
This is kind of this little format that is used to log in as dictionaries.
字典中 立马有一个键
And inside this dictionary there's a key right off the bat
叫作photos 这是另一个字典
called, "Photos" which is another dictionary.
这个字典中 有处在哪一页
And inside that dictionary there's which page this is --
总共有98000页
98,000 pages available, okay?
每一页有250项
250 items each.
Flickr上发生有很多事情
So a lot going on in Flickr.
这里有另外一个键 这个键的值是一个数组
And there's another key here, and the value of this key is an array.
这是照片的数组
And this is an array of the photos.
每一个都是一个字典
Each one of which is a dictionary.
可以看到有很多东西
And you can see there's a lot of stuff
在这些字典中 包括这里的照片标题
in these dictionaries including the title of the photo right here.
然后还有这个
And there's also this one right here.
描述
Description.
也就是照片的描述
Which is a description of the photo.
这个其实是另一个字典
And this one's actually another dictionary.
其中有一个键 这是实际的描述
And inside it is a key that's the actual description --
这个的描述是空的
this one had a blank description.
从这个照片中获得值有些复杂
So this one's going to be a little more tricky to get this value out of this photo.
无论如何 我们需要取出这些东西
But anyway, we're going to have to pull this stuff
以一种古怪的格式从字典中去取
out of this dictionary in this kind of odd format.
我们下面就来做这个
So let's just do that.
要从这里获得照片 我们可以这样写代码
So we can get the photos out of there by saying how about this:
propertyListResults valueForKeyPath
propertylist resultsvalue forkeypath.
然后在FlickrFetcher中
And then in Flickr fetcher,
我有一个很棒的#define定义 来获得这些照片
I have a nice little pound sign define here to get those photos --
一开始就从照片字典中取出照片数组
that photo array out of the photos dictionary at the beginning.
不过这里有一个点 这很有趣
But this has a dot in it which is interesting.
点意思是说 这个键
A dot means this key --
这个键 在这个键的字典内
this key, inside of this key -- the dictionary for this key.
这相当于追随字典中的字典
So it's kind of like following dictionaries inside dictionaries.
这个就是这样了
That's what this thing does.
我要用到这个 不过要让它工作
So I'm going to use this, but to make it work
我们需要使用valueForKeyPath方法
we have to use this value for key path method
而不是使用objectForKey
instead of using object for key, right?
像常规字典方法中那样
Which would be a normal dictionary method.
我打算这样做
So I'm going to do that.
我要处理太多方括号的问题
I'm going to deal with the too many square brackets issue.
好 这就能从中取出相片
Okay. So that is going to pull those photos out of there.
现在 照片以字典数组的形式存在
So now I have the photos as an array of dictionaries.
我打算把我的模型设为这个
And I'm just going to set my model to be that.
这不会太难
So that wasn't too hard.
有问题
Question?
问null和nil的区别
What's the difference between null and nil?
问得很好
Okay that's a good question.
nil意思是对象指针是0
Nil means an object pointer is 0.
指针什么都没指 这就是nil
A pointer that doesn't point to anything is nil.
null是说C指针 什么都没指
Null means a C pointer is -- points to nothing.
这时 这会是一个&error
And in that case that was an ampersand error.
换言之 根据引用 这是NSError
In other words a by reference NS error.
这里不是一个NSError指针
So this is not an NS error pointer.
而是一个NSError
It was an NS error star-star
能理解吗
Do you understand that?
这里这个
This thing right here,
如果我要获得错误 我需要说&error
if I wanted to get the error I would have said &error.
像这样
Like this.
然后是NSError *error
And I would have had NSerror star error.
这将=nil
So this is -- and I -- this would be =nil.
但&error是指向这个指针的一个指针
But an ampersand error is a pointer to this pointer.
那就是null
So that would be null.
好 关于这个有一点不好
Okay. So one thing that's bad about this, this guy right here.
有什么不好
What's that going to do that's bad?
阻塞了主队列
block the main queue.
由于时间有限 这个我不打算修正
So we're not going to fix that because we're going to be time constrained here.
不过这里我警告一下
But I'm going to put a warning in.
这里我加了一个带#号的警告
So there's a nice little pound sound warning thing you can put
你可以在这里添加你自己的警告信息
in that lets you add your own warnings.
这会阻塞主队列所使用的主线程
It really blocks the main thread that is used by the main queue.
这里写一个警告 提醒你以后回头
But this is to basically create a warning and this will remind you to go back
在提交之前修正
and fix this before you submit it, for example,
成品代码中显然不应该有任何警告
because you don't want to have any warnings in your code.
这里我们就不修正了
So we're not going to do this right now
因为还有其它东西要讲
because we want to get on to some of the other things.
我们时间明显不够了
And we're going to run overtime as it is.
最后我会修正这个 然后发布
But I'll do this at the end and then I'll post it.
不过好消息是
But the good news is that
我们在超类中设定了模型 这里
we have set our model back in our superclass, right here.
我们现在有了所有需要的信息 来使用表格
So we have all the information we need now to use our tables --
来使用数据源来加载表格
use datasource to load up that table.
首先这个TableView中有多少section
So first, how many sections in this TableView?
我们将把这些都放到一个大的section中
Well we're going to put it all in one big section.
我们不会有国家这些子section
We're not going to have, like countries or anything else -- any subsections.
只有一个大的section
So we're all going to have one big section.
我们可以把这个警告删掉
So we can get rid of this nice warning actually.
当然 如果我删掉了这整个方法
And of course, if I deleted this whole method,
情况会是一样 因为默认值就是1
that would be the same because the default is one.
而这里 section中的行数 我只有一个大的section
And here, number of rows in section -- well again I only have one section,
所以这里可以返回self.photos count
so I can just return self.photoscount --
这就是我所拥有的照片的量
that's the number of photos I have.
如果section有多个 我就需要返回一个不同的数字
Now if I had multiple sections I would need to find -- return a different number.
不过这里 section只有一个 我这样做就行了
But here I only have one section so I can do that.
然后这里是tableView: cellForRowAtIndexPath:
And then here is our tableView cellForRowAtIndexPath.
这里它问 你在故事板里设了什么
Here it's saying, what did you put in the storyboard
用于单元格的标识符
for the identifier for the cell? Well what did we put?
我们回到这里看看
Let's go look back here.
我们要检查这个单元格
We'll inspect this cell.
属性检查器
The attribute inspector.
再用标识符 这里什么都没设
Reuse identifier; we didn't put anything.
我们试试Flickr Photo Cell
Let's try Flickrphotocell.
这会是一个很好的名字
That would be a good name for that.
这里 在代码中
And so now here in our code,
我们要确保写的是相同的东西
we want to make sure we put the same thing here.
这样它就能知道
And that's how it's going to know
一遍又一遍地去复制这个原型
to duplicate this particular prototype cell over and over.
顺便说下 我们还可以把这设为标题
We could also, by the way, set this to maybe do subtitle.
按任何方式把这个单元格设置成我们想要的
Kind of set this thing up the way that we want, this cell.
让正确的东西得到复制
So that it gets copied -- the right thing we want gets copied.
好 现在我们有了单元格
Okay so we have this cell now, okay,
从这里的dequeueReusableCellWithIdentifier
from the Dequeue Reusable Cell with Identifier there.
然后我们需要对单元格进行配置
And then we need to configure the cell.
配置时 我们需要来自模型的信息
Well to configure the cell, we need the information from our model.
我们需要获取字典
So we need to get the dictionary
对应于这个索引路径处的照片
for the photo that's at this index path.
在这个行和section处
In other words this row and section.
我们还是只有一个大的section 因此我们需要的只是
And again, we only have one big section, so we really just need the photo that's
数组中特定位置的照片
at that place in the array.
这将是photos[indexPath.row]
So that will be photossub indexpath.row.
如果这里有多个section
I would use indexpath.
我就要用indexPath.section 你们作业中就是如此
section if I had multiple sections like you're going to have.
现在我有了照片
So now I have the photo.
我有了你们看到的这个字典
I have that dictionary that you saw --
这里有一些字典
there were a bunch of dictionaries there.
下面来配置单元格
So let's configure the cell.
将这个的textLabel设为photo…
Let's set the text label of that one to be, let's say the photo.
这里我要使用相同的valueForKeyPath
And I'm going to use this same value for keypath here,
避免Flickr的这些东西里面有点
in case any of these things have Flickr have dots in them.
我们import FlickrFetcher
Let's import Flickr fetcher.
FlickrFetcher也有所有这些东西
Flicker fetcher also has all of these things
用于照片内的键
for the keys inside of a photo.
位置内的键 你会需要这个
The keys inside of a place -- which you'll need.
有些键在各种不同的东西里面
Some keys that are in kind of all different things.
我们到这里
And so let's go here.
我们需要FLICKR_PHOTO_TITLE
We want Flickr photo title.
像这样
Like that.
好 然后我们要说detailTextLabel
Alright. And then we'll say the detail text label --
这是那个副标题 我们这里用photo valueForKeyPath
that's the little subtitle -- we'll do photo value forkeypath.
我们需要那个 因为这个有点
And we need that because this one has dots.
也就是描述
And that is the description.
描述在这里是description._content
And the description one -- as you'll see here -- is description. underbarcontent.
如果你回头去看Flickr
And if you remember -- if you go back and look at the Flickr thing,
你就会知道这里为什么是description._content
you'll see why this is description. underbarcontent.
我们有了这个
So we got that.
我们返回单元格 这就够了
We return to the cell, and that's really all we need to do.
我们可以运行这个
So let's go ahead and run this.
这里我们得到了那个警告
Okay, we got that warning there.
阻塞主线程
Block main thread.
在到Flickr取回信息时 这个现在确实阻塞了主线程
And this is blocking the main thread right now as it goes out to Flickr to fetch.
不过它还是获得了信息
But it did get it.
这里有一系列图片
So here's a whole bunch of photos.
有些有副标题 有些没有
Some of them have subtitles; some not.
这很酷 我们可以点它们
Okay. That's cool. Cool. We can click on them.
不过我们还要确保 点击照片时能够看到照片
But it'd be sure nice if we could see these photos when we click on them.
显然 我们需要segue来做到这一点
But of course we need to do a segue to do that.
下面我们就来做这个
So let's go ahead and do that.
回到这里
So let's go back to here.
这个segue很容易做
And you know, this segue is really easy to do.
回到我们的iPhone故事板
Let's go back to our iPhone storyboard here.
我们需要
What we need though is the --
用到Imaginarium中的那个美妙的图像视图控制器
what we want is from Imaginarium, we want that nice, image view controller.
好 看看怎么得到这个
Okay, well watch how we can get that.
我要回到Imaginarium
I'm going to go back to my Imaginarium.
这是Imaginarium
Here's Imaginarium.
首先我要把图像视图控制器代码
First of all I'm going to take the image view controller code
从一个项目拖动到另一个中
and just drag it from one project to another.
这完全是合法的 这里我会复制它
That's perfectly legal. I'm going to copy it in this case.
你也可以关联它们 但要小心
You could link them, but be careful if you do that.
更有趣的是
But even more amazingly, I'm actually going to go
我要到故事板 抓取这个场景
to the storyboard and grab this scene right here --
这个拥有滚动视图等各种东西的场景
this scene that has all this scroll view and all this stuff in it.
将它复制粘贴到Shutterbug的故事板中
And copy it and go over to this storyboard in Shutter Bug and paste it.
它照做了 只是找到它的问题
It did do it. It's just a question of finding it.
放到一边 好了
Put it over on the side, there it is.
好 现在我有了这个
Okay. So now I have this thing here.
由于所有这些关联都是根据名称来的
And all of the links that were in here, since they're all
只要我还有这个类 这些就仍然能够工作
by name, all will still work as long as I have this particular class.
这里是图像视图控制器
Which is image view controller.
它在这里还是将其设置为图像视图控制器
It even still sets the thing here to be an image view controller.
看看这些东西 它们还是关联在一起的
And if I go look at this -- all these things, they're linked -- they're still linked up.
我对这里的滚动表示抱歉
Sorry for the scrolling here.
可以看到这里的活动指示器 它们都关联在一起
But see, you can see the activity indicator, that's all linked up.
因为关联都是通过名称来的
Because it's all being done by name.
我们有了这个美妙的东西
So we have this nice thing.
下面来segue
So we'll -- let's segue to it.
我们使用control拖动… 我们有这个单元格 抱歉
We're just going to control drag -- we got this cell right here, sorry.
这个单元格 control拖动它 到这里
This cell and we're just going to control drag from it to here.
我们要把这放到导航控制器中
Let's do -- we're going to put this in a navigation controller.
我们要push
So we'll push.
这是我们的东西 我们需要一个很好的名称用于segue
Here's our thing. We need a nice name for our segue here.
就叫Display Photo 显示照片
We'll call this display photo. Oops display photo.
这里叫什么其实都行
We can call it again, anything we want.
把这些都嵌入到导航控制器中
Let's put this stuff all in a navigation controller -- embed in navigation controller.
我们有一个很好的UI
So we have an nice UI here.
我们几乎什额外工作都不需要做
Really, with almost no work for us to develop.
在这里 我们可以直接把这称作Shutterbug
While we're here, let's go ahead and call this one Shutter Bug.
这个的标题则依照照片的标题来设定
We will set the title of this one, based on the title of the photo.
我们只需要做什么就能让segue开始工作
So all we need to do to make a segue work is what?
prepareForSegue
Prepare for segue.
我们回到这里 进行prepareForSegue
So let's go back and do prepare for segue.
实际上 下面这里它被注释掉了
It's actually commented out down here.
取消注释
Plug it back in.
这里我们只需要
And all -- the only trick we need to know here is
从这个sender获得索引路径
that we need to get the index path from this sender.
也就是点击的TableView单元格
Which is the TableView cell that was clicked on.
让我们这样做
So let's do that.
NSIndexPath *indexPath = [self.tableView…
NSindexpath. indexpath=self .tableview --
记住 所有TableView控制器都有这个tableView
remember all TableView controllers have this TableView
属性 让你用于获取这个
property that you can use to get this stuff.
然后我需要indexPathForCell:sender
And I want indexpath forcellsender.
好 这样我就有了这个索引路径
Okay. So now I have this index path.
如果我要想保险 我还可以说 if (indexPath)
If I want to be really safe, I could say, ifindexpath.
这样一来 如果这个sender…
That way if somehow this sender, you know,
我还可以更保险一些
I could even be super safe and say,
我可以说  if ([sender isKindOfClass:
ifsender iskindofclass
[UITableViewCell class]])
uitableview cell class.
有些人想要非常小心
Some people are really -- want to be careful about,
使用ID 他们想使用内省
you know, using ID and they want to use introspection.
我显然能够明白你为什么要这样做
And I certainly appreciate why you want to do that.
有时 让app崩溃其实更好
Sometimes it's better to let your app just crash.
这有时能够帮你更快地找到bug
And when you do that you'll find the bugs faster sometimes.
或者 在其中一些if中 你可以加入else log
Or in some of these ifs, you want to put elseloga --
关于内部错误或是别的什么
you know, an internal error or something like that.
无论如何 我们有了这个索引路径
But anyway, we've got this index path.
它不是nil 于是我们能找到这个TableView单元格
It's not nil, so we were able to find this TableView cell
在这个TableView中 这很好 我们开了个好头
in this TableView so that's good. We're off to a good start.
看看这是不是Display Photo那个segue
Let's see if this is the display photo segue.
如果是 我们看看
If it is, let's see
如果segue.destinationViewController isKindOfClass
if the segue destination view controller is kind of class --
是那类图像视图控制器 因为这就是我们要的
that image view controller class, because that's what we need it to be.
图像视图控制器
Image view controller.
如果它是一个图像视图控制器
So if it is an image view controller class,
那就很棒了
then we are good to go.
我们要的一切就都有了
Kind of got everything we need at this point.
这里我要创建一个小的辅助方法
And I'm actually going to create a little helper method here,
也就是prepareImageViewController
which is prepare imageviewcontroller
ImageViewController
imageviewcontroller
toDisplayPhoto
todisplayphoto
NSDictionary photo 这只是一个
NSdictionaryphoto. So this is just going to be something --
帮助实际准备的辅助方法
a little helper thing that does the actual preparation.
这很简单
And this is really easy.
ivc.imageURL 记得Imaginarium中的这个吗
Ivc.imageurl -- remember that from the Imaginarium?
这就是图像视图控制器公共API
That's what the image view controller's public API is.
我们需要为这张照片获取URL
We need to get the URL for this photo.
FlickrFetcher也可以帮我们完成这个
And it turns out Flickr fetcher can help us with that too.
FlickrFetcher
Flickr fetcher.
这里有个URLforPhoto
There's a thing called URL for photo.
给它一个photo字典
And we just give it the photo dictionary
它使用字典内的东西来获取URL
and it uses stuff inside the dictionary to get the URL.
这里可以选择我们想要的格式 我要选择large格式
And then we can pick what format we want, and I'm going to pick the large format.
这里的选项有large original square三种
The choices there are large, original, or square.
square就像一个缩略图 非常小
Square is like a thumbnail -- really small --
只在需要缩略图时才用这个
so only use that if you need a thumbnail,
这次作业中不需要这样
which you don't need for this assignment.
original是高清
An original is high res.
large则是比较好的大小 例如1024x768这些
And then large, it's kind of a good size, like 1024 x 768 or something like that.
我还说 我要把这个的标题
And then I told you also I'm going to set the title of this thing
设为photo valueForKeyPath
to be the photovalue forkeypath
FLICKR_PHOTO_TITLE
flickrphototitle.
这样我就还能得到图像视图控制器的标题
So I'm going to set the title of that image view controller as well.
下面调用这个辅助方法 prepareImageViewController
So now let's call this little helper thing prepareimage viewcontroller.
图像视图控制器是segue.destinationViewController
The image view controller is segue.destination view controller,
toDisplayPhoto
to display photo.
照片是self.photosIndexPath.row
The photo is self.photosindex path.row.
都理解吗
Everyone understand that?
我只是在这个索引路径处访问了模型
Okay. I'm just reaching into my model here at this index path
这是sender
that was the sender.
看看这能否奏效
Alright? So let's see if this works.
这还是阻塞了主线程 我只是懒得管它
Again, this is blocking our main thread here, which is a bummer.
你们知道怎么处理它
You'd know how to not do that.
现在 我们就到了UI导航控制器中
So here we have now, we're in a UI navigation controller.
很酷 我们有这个
That's cool. We got that.
让我点击一点东西
Let's go ahead and click on something
这里其实有些无伤大雅
that hopefully is innocuous here it is.
可以放大和缩小
And we can zoom in and out.
很酷 我们可以回头点点别的
That's cool. Alright we can go back and click on something else.
另一张罗马照片 这是圆形竞技场
Another Rome picture.That was the Coliseum.
但愿这样也能行
Okay. Hopefully things are work here too.
非常酷
So that's pretty cool.
很轻松就获得了一个很强大的app
That was pretty easy to get a pretty powerful app together.
我们只花了20分钟
We did it in about 20 minutes.
再在iPad上做这个
So now let's do this on iPad.
其实这也很简单
This turns out to be quite easy as well.
我们前往iPad故事板
So we're going to go to the iPad storyboard.
我把iPad故事板上移到了iPhone故事板附近
I'm actually going to move the iPad storyboard up near the iPhone storyboard.
它现在是空白的
So it's blank right now.
我要拖出SplitView控制器
And I'm going to drag out a SplitView controller.
它在这里
So here it is right here.
如果这里不是iPad故事板 它将不会出现在这里
Now this will not be in this list if this is not an iPad storyboard.
在处理iPhone的情况时
So sometimes you have your iPhone on,
你会发现这里没有SplitView控制器
and there's no SplitView controller, you're like, what?
不要惊讶 只有iPad中才有
Where's the SplitView controller? Okay you've got to be -- selected your iPad one.
我把这个拖出来
So I'm going to bring this out.
这是SplitView控制器
Here's the SplitView controller.
注意这些是免费提供给我的
Notice it gave me these for free.
我不喜欢免费提供的东西
I got what I paid for, which is I don't want either of these things.
我想要iPad中我的master是这个
So I want my master in my iPad one to be this right here.
这个Shutterbug列表
This Shutter Bug list.
我还希望detail是图像视图
And I want my detail to be that image view, right?
我这里只需要全选复制
So I'm just going to select all and copy here.
回到iPad故事板 粘贴
And go over to my iPad storyboard and paste.
放到这里
Put some in here.
看起来有些乱
Kind of makes a bit of a mess of it.
把它移动一下
But let's move it around here.
这是一样的东西
So here -- this is the same thing.
看起来不一样 因为大小有不同 实际上是一样的
Doesn't look the same because the sizes are different, but it's the same thing we had.
我要把这两个设置成master
And I'm just going to make this -- these two be the master
我只需要从SplitView控制器control拖动到这里
by control dragging from my SplitView controller over here.
我可以选master或detail 这里选master
And I can pick master or detail -- I'll take master.
然后我要把这个control拖动到这里
And then I'm going to control drag from here over to this guy,
将其设置为detail
and make that the detail.
这样我就有了master和detail
So now I've got master and detail.
这正是我要的
Exactly what I want.
我将得到一个SplitView 其左侧很窄
So I'm going to have a SplitView that has a little narrow thing
这些是照片的列表
on the left, which is the list of photos.
大空间则将是我选择的照片
And the big space is going to be the photo that I chose.
不过这里还有一个小问题
I've got one slight problem here though,
也就是 这个segue还在这里
which is this little segue still is here.
因此点击这里的东西时
So when I click on things here, it's going to try
它会尝试把这个视图控制器替换成这个
to replace this little view controller with this.
我不希望这样
And I don't want that.
我要删掉这个segue
So I'm going to delete this segue.
这就得到了我想要的
Now that gives me what I want.
不过还有问题 我点这里它就不会更新了
But now the problem is if I click in here, it's not going to update this.
怎么办呢
So how do I do that?
这就可以用到委托方法didSelectRowAtIndexPath
That's doing what that delegate method did select row at index path.
我们可以回到这里
So we're just going to go to back to here.
我们将有一个新的pragma
And we're going to have another -- a new pragma here.
#pragma mark UITableViewDelegate
#Pragmamark uitableviewdelegate --
不是Datasource 而是Delegate
not datasource but delegate --
在这里键入时
and we're going to type here
可以看到这里有很多UITableViewDelegate
and start typing, and you can see there's a lot of UI TableView delegates.
我们需要的是这个 didSelectRowAtIndexPath
So we want the one right here. See it did select row at index path.
我们需要这个
We want that one.
这里我们需要获得SplitView控制器中的detail
And here what we need to do is get the detail in the SplitView controller.
我告诉过你们这是…
And I told you that that is --
detail视图控制器是
the detail view controller
self.splitViewController.viewControllers[1]
is self.splitviewcontroller. viewcontrollerssub1.
还是那句话 如果我们不在SplitView中
And again, if we're not in a SplitView --
要知道 这段代码也可以在iPhone上运行
because this code is going to be executed on the iPhone as well.
如果我们不在SplitView中 这个会是nil
And if we're not in a SplitView this is going to be nil.
这整个也将是nil
So this whole thing is going to be nil.
这就什么都做不了 因为这也将是nil
So this is going to do nothing because this is going to be nil.
这是一段很棒的代码
So this is great code.
我不需要说 if iPad 怎么怎么
I didn't have to say if iPad or anything.
只有在SplitView控制器中时 这个才会发生
It's just this is only going to happen if I'm in a SplitView controller.
这里我稍微稳妥一点
So I'm going to be a little, you know, worried here,
我说 isKindOfClass
and I'm going to say iskindofclass --
确保这在图像视图控制器中
and make sure that that's an image view controller.
如果它是 我就将
But if it is, then I'm just going
调用下面这里的prepareImageViewController
to call my prepare image controller thing down here,
这将是detail
and this is going to be the detail.
照片将是self.photos[indexPath.row]
And the photo is going to be self.photos indexpath.row.
因为它给我的是选中的索引路径
Because it gives me the index path that got selected.
这就是这里需要发生的事情
Right? So that's all that needs to happen here.
我们运行着试下
So let's just go ahead and run this.
哦 我应该在iPad上运行
Oops. Well it's running on an iPad how about that?
在真实设备上运行 如何
Well we'll run it on the real device how about.
好 还是一样 这里被阻塞了 直到内容被加载完毕
Okay. So again, it blocked until it had loaded that thing,
这比较不幸
which is unfortunate.
转轮在转
That thing is spinning.
我不喜欢这个 因为我还没有选任何照片
I don't really like that because I haven't picked a photo yet.
免得忘记了 我现在就回到iPad故事板
So I'm just going to go quickly, before I even forget, go back to my iPad storyboard --
而且只处理iPad故事板 另一个则不用
and only in my iPad storyboard, not in the other one.
我要选
I'm going to pick
那个活动视图控制器 这里
that activity view controller, which is right here.
我要检查它
And I'm going to inspect it.
让它不要一开始就出现动画
And I'm going to not start it out animating.
另一个故事板中仍然会这样做
It's still going to do it in my other one --
这没问题 因为那个是在创建一个新的视图控制器
which is okay because that's creating a new view controller
每次segue时都是如此 这个则不一样
every time I segue -- but not in this one --
不过我希望在点击图片时 例如罗马 它会加载罗马
but hopefully if I click on a picture -- like Rome here -- it loads up Rome.
这是罗马
And so here is Rome.
我可以放大
I can zoom in.
我还可以选另一张图 例如巴克莱中心
If I pick another picture, let's say Barclays Center -- That's --
这没问题 我猜
oh well, that looks okay I guess.
这个能行
This worked.
但有点偏离
It's kind of a little off.
可以看到 顶部有白色
You'll see there's the white at the top.
这并不很对
That's not really quite right.
左侧有白色区域 看到左侧的白色区域了吗
And this white on the left -- you see the white on the left --
左侧的白色区域是怎么回事
what's going on with the white on the left?
为什么会有这个
Why is this happening?
我们的图像视图控制器设计得并没有这么好
Well we didn't design our image view controller that well
能像这样再利用
to be reused like this.
这个图像视图控制器
This image view controller is staying
一直待在屏幕上并被再利用
on screen all the time and being reused.
它其中会有一些bug
And it has a couple of bugs in it that are causing
如果我放大了 然后换另外一张照片
when I zoom in, and then I replace it with another photo.
首先 它不会重置缩放尺度
First of all it's not resetting the zoom scale back
为1 这本是应该的
down to one -- which it should --
而且在缩放匹配时
but also it's sizing to fit
它会不再处在可滚动区域的左上角
and causing it to no longer be in the upper left-hand corner of our scrollable area.
我们快速修正一下这个
So let's fix that real quick.
到图像视图控制器
Let's go to our image view controller.
修正很简单
Those are easy fixes.
每次设定图像时 我们都要让scrollView
Every time we set an image, we're going to take our scrollView
重置缩放尺度为1
and reset it's zoom scale back to one.
这里我们不再仅仅使用sizeToFit
And instead of just doing size to fit right here,
我们打算明确将图像视图框
we're going to explicitly set the image views frame
设为一个我们要生成的矩形 它处在原点
to a rectangle that we're going to make, which is at the origin.
而且宽度是图像的宽度 高度是图像的高度
And is the images size.width and the images size.height.
这样bug就修正了
Okay. So that will fix that bug.
我们不再使用sizeToFit
We don't want size to fit anymore because we're doing --
而是使用图像本身大小
this is sizing it to fit essentially.
这个bug被修正了 这很好
So we fixed that bug. That's nice.
另外还有一点不是太好
The other thing that's not so great about this
要是在顶部有个标题就好了
is it'd be nice to have a title along the top.
我们设置了标题
We set the title,
但它并没有出现在detail一侧的任何地方
but it doesn't appear anywhere on the detail side.
要是能有一个标题就好了 就像这边这样
Right? So it'd be nice if we had a title just like on the -- this side over here.
这上面显示说Shutterbug
That says Shutter Bug at the top, it'd be nice
右边我们也希望这里有 Jake at the Breakers
if it said Jake at the Breakers over here on the right.
怎么做呢
So how are we going to do that?
这个技巧其实我原来就讲过
I'm going to do that with that little trick I told you.
我要到我的iPad故事板
I'm just going to go here to my iPad storyboard.
选取这个detail视图 然后
I'm going to pick this detail view and I'm just going
将它嵌入到导航控制器中
to embed it in a navigation controller.
这样问题就能修复了
And that's just going to fix that problem.
运行着试下 我们修正了三个问题
So let's go ahead and run -- well we've fixed three problems there.
下面看看问题有没有真正解决
Let's make sure all these problems actually got fixed.
你们会看到 问题是修正了 但又会有新问题产生
And you're going to see that we fixed them, but we introduced a problem as well.
现在是这样了 这个会更好
Okay so we have this -- oh this is better.
上面这里有预留空间
We've got this space on the top right there.
但愿我们在点击罗马或是免费票时
Hopefully when we click on something like Rome or free tickets.
我们会得到… 哦 什么都没显示
We'll get -- oh it's not working anymore.
为什么右边什么都没显示
Why is it not putting anything on the right?
原因在于 detail被改变 它不再是图像视图控制器
And the reason for that is we changed the detail to not be an image view controller.
而是一个导航控制器
Instead, it's now a navigation controller.
但我们这里更新didSelectRowAtIndexPath的代码
So our code over here, where we update with didselectrow atindexpath.
却在检验detail是不是图像视图控制器
It's checking if detail is kind of class image view controller.
这注定失败 因为它不是
And that's failing because it's not.
不过这个很好修正
But this is an easy fix as well.
我们只需要说 if detail
We're just going to say if the detail
isKindOfClass
is kind of class,
UINavigationController
UI navigation controller.
如果detail属于UI导航控制器这一类
So if there's a UI navigation controller in the detail,
那么detail实际上就是UINavigationController
then the detail is really the UI navigation controller
detail.viewControllers firstObject
detail.viewcontrollers firstobject.
也就是导航控制器中的根视图控制器
In other words the root view controller in navigation controller. So I'm just --
如果detail是导航控制器
if the detail is in the navigation controller,
我就会进去获得它的根视图控制器
I'm just going to look in and get its root view controller instead.
这样问题就解决了
So fixes that problem.
但愿吧
Hopefully.
好 再次试试罗马
Okay. So let's try Rome again --
好 现在上面有了罗马的标题
oh now we got the title Rome up there at the top.
哪怕是放大以后
Even if we zoom in on this and switch
再换到别的照片 缩放尺度还是回到了1
to another one that's different, it went back to zoom scale one,
左边也没有任何白色边缘
and we don't have white on the left edge, right?
这次 我再把图像缩小一些
So even if -- again, we'll make it really small this time.
点击罗得岛纽波特
We'll click to Newport, Rhode Island here.
缩放尺度回到了1 而且没有白色边缘
Okay it went back to zoom scale of 1 with no white.
所有问题都解决了
So we fixed all of our problems. We didn't have that
我们也没有了一开始的转轮动画
the animating thing -- animating at the beginning
当然 选择新照片时 动画显然会出现 这很好
although it does animate when we pick a new 1, so that's all good.
看起来非常棒
So this is really looking good.
我做这个是因为这是典型的循环渐进过程
So this is a typical kind of -- I wanted to do this because it's kind
只是有些加速了 毕竟这里只是课堂演示
of a typical iteration process; speeded up of course because we're in a demo here.
一开始 你发现出了某种问题
Where you find something that doesn't quite work.
怎么回事
Hmm. What's going on?
你回到代码 然后修正错误 如此往复
You go back to your code; you have to fix some things, etcetera.
最后 我们其实还有一个问题
So the last thing that I want to show -- now we do have another problem here.
我一直都是在横屏模式展示 下面来看竖屏
I've been showing this in landscape. Let's look at this thing in portrait.
在竖屏中 这很棒
Okay. This is awesome in portrait. This is great.
只是我无法访问master
Except for I can't get at the master.
我没办法换照片 要换照片只能回到横屏
I can't change my photo. It's -- the only way to change a photo is to go back here.
这显然不好
So that's not so nice.
我们希望在左上角有一个按钮
It would be nice if we had this button in the upper left
能够让我们选择照片
over here, that would bring out that thing.
我们快速做一下
So let's do that real quick.
这其实很容易搞定 因为这里我们处在导航控制器中
That turns out to be quite easy to do, because we're in a navigation controller there.
我们打算在图像控制器中这样做
And we're going to do that in the image controller.
原因在于 它处在detail上
The reason I'm going to do it in the image view controller is because it's on the detail.
它在这里可见
It's what's visible right here.
我要将它弄成SplitView控制器委托
So I'm going to make it be the SplitView controller delegate.
到下面这里
So just go down to the bottom here.
pragma mark UISplitViewControllerDelegate
Pragmamark UIsplitviewcontroller delegate.
我打算使用awakeFromNib
Okay. And I'm going to do this awake from NIB.
我这里说 self.splitViewController.delegate = self
I'm going to say self.splitview controller.delegate =self.
在awakeFromNib中 我可以这样做
Okay. That's okay to do in awake from NIB
因为这到awakeFromNib发生时将会设定
because this will be set by the time awake from NIB happens.
虽然这非常非常早
Even though that's really, really early.
我得到了一个警告 因为我还需要
I'm getting a warning because I have to say
UISplitViewControllerDelegate
UI SplitView controller delegate.
好 现在我还要在协议中实现这些方法
Okay. Now I've got to implement the methods in that protocol.
它们是这样的 splitView 这里有很多东西
They look like this, SplitView so there's a whole bunch of them here.
我要用的是
Actually I'm going to do the one
决定master是否隐藏的那个
which says whether to hide the thing first --
也就是这个
that's this one.
Tab 上面这里留点空间
So tab. Up here I'm going to make some space
这样就不会一直滚到底部
so this stops scrolling all the way to the bottom.
这个是说 我在特定朝向下是否隐藏master
So this is the one that says should I hide the master in a certain orientation?
这里我想说 隐藏master…
And I'm going to say, only hide it --
看看我记不记得这个叫什么
let's see if I can remember what this thing is called --
仅当UI界面朝向是竖屏的时候
UI interface orientation is portrait.
我将只在竖屏模式隐藏master
Okay. So in portrait mode only, I'm going to hide the master.
隐藏后 我就需要处理这个splitView…
So now when I hide it, I have to do this SplitView.
我要做两件事
I have to do these two things, will hide --
willHide和willShow
will hide and will show.
willHide在这里
So let's do will hide right there.
然后是splitView willShow
And then let's do with SplitView will show.
好长
That's a mouthful.
好 我们这样做
Okay. So let's do that.
由于我处在导航控制器中
And because I'm in a navigation controller,
这些都非常非常容易实现
these turn out to be really, really easy to implement.
当我隐藏时 它会给我这个栏按钮
Okay. When I hide it gives me this bar button right here.
我只需要把这个放入我的导航项目
And I just need to put that in my navigation item
这样它就会作为左侧栏按钮项目出现
so that it will appear as the left bar button item.
这里还有一个技巧
I'm going to do another little trick here.
也就是 我想要我的图像视图控制器
Is that I want my image view controller,
我不需要它知道Flickr照片的任何信息
I don't want it to know anything about that Flickr photo thing.
因此 我可以将栏按钮项目的标题设为master的标题
So I'm actually going to set this bar button item's title equal to the master title.
无论被隐藏的master的标题是什么
So whatever the title of the master that's being hidden,
这个按钮都将使用这个标题
that's what I'm going to make that little button say as its title.
我需要回到iPad故事板来设置这个
So I better go back to my iPad storyboard and set this,
也就是 我要设置它的标题 可以在故事板中设
which is, the thing I better set its title, which I can set in the storyboard.
这个我们称之为Shutterbug
We'll call this Shutter Bug.
这会让SplitView控制器的这段代码更通用一些
So that's going to make this code for the SplitView controller more generic here.
然后 当这个东西消失时
And then when the thing goes away,
我要把这个左侧栏按钮项目设置为nil
I'm just going to set this left bar button item equal to nil
让那个东西消失
to make that thing go away.
这就修正了
Alright? So that fixes that.
看看结果怎样
Let's go see what that looks like.
好 这里是横屏模式
Okay. So here I have in landscape it shows.
进入竖屏 master没了
When I go here to portrait it goes away.
不过左上角有了一个按钮
But now I have this button in the upper left.
点击 master就会出来
If I click it, it slides that thing out.
点别的地方 它就会消失
If I click somewhere else it goes away.
我可以点这里 获得某张照片
So I can click here, get some photo.
或许罗马会好点
Maybe Rome would be better.
我不知道巴克莱中心那个是什么东西
I don't know what the Barclays center's about.
罗马更安全一些
Rome seems safe.
这是罗马
So here's Rome, right?
这很好
And this is nice, we can do this.
如果我们想要别的 我把这个弄出来
But if I want something else, I can just slide this thing out.
再下面 再找一张不同的罗马照片
Look down; find a different Rome.
好理解吧
Makes sense?
回到横屏模式 按钮就消失了
If I slide back to landscape, you take that button away. That button is no longer there.
这就是那个委托的作用
Okay. So that's what that delegate's doing.
这让我们更容易实现
It was easy for us to implement
因为我们把detail放入了一个SplitView控制器
because we put the detail into a SplitView controller.
总想做到这一点 并没有那么简单
It wouldn't always be so easy to do that.
最后我要做一件事 也就是修正
The last thing I'm going to do here is fix that problem
主线程阻塞的问题
with the blocking of the main thread.
我打算很快地做一下 看好了
I'm going to do this super fast. So hang onto your hats.
在这里
I'm going to do that here.
我将使用一种不同以往的做法
And I'm going to do it in a different way than we did before.
因为我想教给你们另一种做法
Because I want to show you a different way to do this.
这里 我打算创建我自己的队列
Which is, I'm going to create my own queue.
dispatch_queue_t
So dispatchunderbar queueunderbarT --
这里我叫它fetchQ
fetchqueue I'll call it.
我要用dispatch_queue_create创建它
I'm going to create it with dispatch create queue create.
我将称它为flicker fetcher
I'm going to call it Flickerfetcher -- that's just the name I'm going to call it.
它是一个串行队列
And it's a serial queue.
这样我就创建了我自己的队列
So I just created my own queue.
一个全新的队列
Brand new queue.
有了我自己的队列后 我就可以
And now that I have my own queue I'm just going to
dispatch_async到这个队列上
dispatch async onto that queue.
一段代码
A block.
这段代码中间将是这些阻塞的内容
And that block is just going to have this blocking stuff in it.
所有这些东西
All this stuff here.
不过self.photos
But self.photos -- okay?
不需要在这里
Which does need to be in here,
很不幸 这会做处在UI中的事情
unfortunately this is going to do stuff on -- that's in the UI so it needs
因此需要分派回主线程
to be dispatched back to the main thread.
那个放到那里
Alright. Put that there.
这个放到这里
Put this here.
这样做之后
So that's going to do this.
主线程就不会被阻塞了
We're not going to block the main thread anymore.
我们通过创建自己的队列完成了这个工作
So this is a way to do it by creating your own queue.
这里我们没有使用URLSession
Instead of doing all that stuff we do with the URL session
而是像这样做了
and all that stuff we can just do this.
那里有问题吗
Is that a question right there?
请讲
Yeah.
为什么这里我们不需要使用weak self
Why do we not have to do weak self in this thing?
因为这段代码没有太强地被我们自身所引用
Because this block is not held on too strongly by ourselves.
它很强地引用了我们
We -- it holds us strongly,
但我们没有很强地引用它 这就没关系了
but we don't hold it strongly so we're good to go.
最后我还要做一件事 这里我将同时来做
And the last thing I'm going to do -- which I'll do at the same time here --
也就是刷新那个 因为这很容易做到
is that little refresh thing, because that's really easy to do.
先在iPad版上来做 两个版本我们都会考虑
And let's do that here on the iPad version -- we'll have to do it on both versions,
这里是我们的TableView
but here's our TableView right here.
我们希望有一个刷新转轮在刷新时转动
And we wanted to have a little refresh spinner when all that business is going on.
要做到这个 我们可以用检查器
So to do that we just inspect it.
下面这里 可以看到它说刷新
And down here you see it says refreshing, right here.
这里我们选启用
So we're going to say enabled.
这样做之后 在文档大纲中你会看到
And when we did that, in our document outline you'll see
我们这里得到了这个刷新控制
that we got this refresh control right here.
而且我们还可以很轻松地得到下拉支持
And really, for free we can get it -- the pull down support
只要我们在这里把fetchPhotos设为IBAction
if we just make fetch photos here be an IB action.
因为 如果这是IBAction 我们就能control拖动到它
Because if that's an IB action, then we can control drag to it.
因为我们可以control拖动到任何IBAction
Because we can control drag to any IB action.
向下拉会调用这个fetchPhotos
And so now that pull down is going to call this fetch photos.
在fetchPhotos中 我们仍然需要说
Now we still are required, inside this fetch photos,
self.refreshControl beginRefreshing
to say self.refresh controlbegin refreshing.
完成之后 下面这里
And then when we're done, down here.
我们需要说 self.refreshControl endRefreshing
We need to say self.refresh controlendrefreshing.
都懂了吗
Everyone understand this?
这会让转轮开始旋转并刷新
This is going to make things start spinning and make it go down.
这个目标动作让我们能够往下拉
But this target action we did makes it so we can pull down on it.
我们来看看这个
So let's take a look at that.
加载成功 可以看到它在刷新
Okay so it loads up, and you can see it's refreshing.
它正在从Flickr取回数据
See it's doing all the Flickr fetch now instead
同时又不像原来那样阻塞我们的UI
of doing it all before, you know, and blocking our UI.
实际上 如果我下拉它 它又会刷新
And in fact, if I pull down on it, it does it again.
但我的UI仍然可用 因为刷新是在另一个队列中
But my UI is still active because it's doing that in a different queue.
我还是可以四处滚动
So I can still scroll around, but it's doing
同时程序会在后台取回数据进行更新
that fetch in the background and it's going to update this.
Flickr上 这些最新发布只是每15分钟左右更新一次
Flickr only updates this most recently posted thing every 15 minutes or so,
因此这里列表没变化
so that's why you're not seeing the list change.
如果我等十分钟再来刷新 列表肯定会发生变化
But if I waited 10 minutes and did it, then that would happen.
就这些了
And so there we go.
顺便说下 如果只是部分拉下 它不会刷新
By the way, if you pull this down partially it doesn't do it.
需要拉到很下 转轮才会旋转 刷新才会开始
You have to pull it down all the way and start it spinning.
这是UI的一部分
This is part of the UI.
确保这就是你想要的
To make sure you really wanted that.
以上就是我的全部演示了
That's all I wanted to show you.
很抱歉今天有些拖堂了
Sorry to have -- run a little over -- a little extra time.
有问题的现在可以来提 谢谢
I'm here if you have any questions. Thank you.
更多内容 请访问我校官网stanford.edu
> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.